<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: screenos | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="http://tunnelsup.github.io/tup/tag/screenos/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tunnelsup.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-29T22:41:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tunnelsup.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[View Interface Statistics on ScreenOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://tunnelsup.github.io/view-interface-statistics-on-screenos/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-06T11:11:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tunnelsup.github.io/view-interface-statistics-on-screenos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Get command to see interface statistics on a SSG/ScreenOS</h2>

<p><code>get counter statistics interface &lt;interface&gt;</code></p>

<p>This will display the following result:<br></p>

<p>```
FLFW1-> get count stati int eth0/2
Hardware counters for interface ethernet0/2:
in bytes      2391954371 | out bytes     2188210410 | early frame            0
in packets    2536213416 | out packets    926090442 | late frame             0
in no buffer           0 | out no buffer          0 | re-xmt limit           0
in overrun             0 | out underrun           0 | drop vlan              0
in coll err            0 | out coll err           0 | out cs lost            0
in misc err            0 | out misc err           0 |                       <br/>
in dma err             0 | out bs pak             0 |                       <br/>
in crc err             0 | out discard            0 |                       <br/>
in align err           0 | out defer              0 |                       <br/>
in short frame         0 | out heartbeat          0 |</p>

<p>Hardware 64-bit counters for interface ethernet0/2:
in bytes                7278066553795 |  out bytes               1376577745130
in ucast                   6831180712 |  out ucast                  5221057738
in mcast                            0 |  out mcast                           0
in bcast                            0 |  out bcast                           0</p>

<p>Total flow counters for interface ethernet0/2:
in bytes      1363202958 | out bytes     2188210410 | tcp proxy              0
in packets    2521677948 | out packets    926090442 | tear drop            387
in vlan                0 | out vlan               0 | in permit     3912073647
out permit    1539534845 | src route              0 | no g-parent            0
ping of death          0 | no gate sess           0 | address spoof          0
in icmp         12232565 | no nat vector         11 | land attack            0
in self                0 | no map                 0 | icmp flood         77599
in un-auth             0 | no conn                0 | no arp entry           0
udp flood              0 | in unk prot            0 | no dip                 0
winnuke                0 | in vpn         222640182 | no gate                0
port scan            194 | in other               0 | no xmit vpnf           0
ip sweep               0 | no mac                 0 | no route               0
tcp out of seq     88121 | mac relearn            0 | no frag sess           0
wrong intf             0 | slow mac               0 | no frag netpak         0
wrong slot             0 | trmng queue            0 | no sa                734
icmp broadcast         0 | trmng drop             0 | no sa policy           0
illegal pak      4739684 | tiny frag              0 | sa inactive        52449
url block              2 | syn frag               0 | sa policy deny         0
encrypt fail           0 | connections            0 | policy deny            0
mp fail                0 | misc prot              0 | auth deny              0
auth fail              2 | loopback drop         16 | big bkstr              0
proc sess              0 | mal url                0 | sessn thresh           0
invalid zone           0 | null zone              0 | no nsp-tunnel          0
IP cls failure         0 | first pak frag        18 | unknown pak     14532135
multiauth drop         0 | multi-DIP drop         0 | tcp sweep              0
udp sweep              0 | tcp check drop         0 |
```</p>

<h2>Deciphering Output</h2>

<p><code>address spoof</code>   Number of suspected address spoofing attack packets received<br>
<code>auth deny</code>   Number of times user authentication was denied<br>
<code>auth fail</code>   Number of times user authentication failed<br>
<code>big bkstr</code>   Number of packets that are too big to buffer in the ARP back store while waiting for MAC-to-IP address resolution<br>
<code>connections</code>   Number of sessions established since the last boot<br>
<code>encrypt fail</code>  Number of failed Point-to-Point Tunneling Protocol (PPTP) packets<br>
<code>*icmp broadcast</code>   Number of ICMP broadcasts received<br>
<code>icmp flood</code>  Number of ICMP packets that are counted toward the ICMP flood threshold<br>
<code>illegal pak</code>   Number of packets dropped because they do not conform to the protocol standards<br>
<code>in arp req</code>  Number of incoming arp request packets<br>
<code>in arp resp</code>   Number of outgoing arp request packets<br>
<code>in bytes</code>  Number of bytes received<br>
<code>in icmp</code>   Number of Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP) packets received<br>
<code>in other</code>  Number of incoming packets that are of a different Ethernet type<br>
<code>in packets</code>  Number of packets received<br>
<code>in self</code>   Number of packets addressed to the Management IP address<br>
<code>*in un auth</code>   Number of unauthorized incoming TCP, UDP, and ICMP packets<br>
<code>*in unk prot</code>  Number of incoming packets using an unknown Ethernet protocol<br>
<code>in vlan</code>   Number of incoming vlan packets<br>
<code>in vpn</code>  Number of IPsec packets received<br>
<code>invalid zone</code>  Number of packets destined for an invalid security zone<br>
<code>ip sweep</code>  Number of packets received and discarded beyond the specified ip sweep threshold<br>
<code>land attack</code>   Number of suspected land attack packets received<br>
<code>loopback drop</code>   Number of packets dropped because they cannot be looped back through the security device. An example of a loopback session is when a host in the Trust zone sends traffic to a MIP or VIP address that is mapped to a server that is also in the Trust zone. The security device creates a loopback session that directs such traffic from the host to the MIP or VIP server. mac relearn Number of times that the MAC address learning table had to relearn the interface associated with a MAC address because the location of the MAC address changed<br>
<code>mac tbl full</code>  Number of times that the MAC address learning table completely filled up<br>
<code>mal url</code>   Number of blocked packets destined for a URL determined to be malicious<br>
<code>*misc prot</code>  Number of packets using a protocol other than TCP, UDP, or ICMP<br>
<code>mp fail</code>   Number of times a problem occurred when sending a PCI message between the master processor module and the processor module<br>
<code>no conn</code>   Number of packets dropped because of unavailable Network Address Translation (NAT) connections<br>
<code>no dip</code>  Number of packets dropped because of unavailable Dynamic IP (DIP) addresses<br>
<code>no frag netpak</code>  Number of times that the available space in the netpak buffer fell below 70%<br>
<code>*no frag sess</code>   The number of times that fragmented sessions were greater than half of the maximum number of NAT sessions<br>
<code>no g-parent</code>   Number of packets dropped because the parent connection could not be found<br>
<code>no gate</code>   Number of packets dropped because no gate was available<br>
<code>no gate sess</code>  Number of terminated sessions because there were no gates in the firewall for them<br>
<code>no map</code>  Number of packets dropped because there was no map to the trusted side<br>
<code>no nat vector</code>   Number of packets dropped because the Network Address Translation (NAT) connection was unavailable for the gate<br>
<code>*no nsp tunnel</code>  Number of dropped packets sent to a tunnel interface to which no VPN tunnel is bound<br>
<code>no route</code>  Number of unroutable packets received<br>
<code>no sa</code>   The number of packets dropped because no Security Associations (SA) was defined<br>
<code>no sa policy</code>  Number of packets dropped because no policy was associated with an SA<br>
<code>*no xmit vpnf</code>   Number of dropped VPN packets due to fragmentation<br>
<code>null zone</code>   Number of dropped packets erroneously sent to an interface bound to the Null zone<br>
<code>nvec err</code>  Number of packets dropped because of NAT vector error<br>
<code>out bytes</code>   Number of bytes sents<br>
<code>out defer</code>   Number of deferred outgoing packets<br>
<code>out packets</code>   Number of packets sent<br>
<code>out defer</code>   Number of deferred outgoing packets<br>
<code>out vlan</code>  Number of outgoing vlan packets<br>
<code>ping of death</code>   Number of suspected Ping of Death attack packets received<br>
<code>policy deny</code>   Number of packets denied by a defined policy<br>
<code>port scan</code>   Number of packets that are counted as a port scan attempt<br>
<code>proc sess</code>   Number of times that the total number of sessions on a processor module exceeded the maximum threshold<br>
<code>sa inactive</code>   Number of packets dropped because of an inactive SA<br>
<code>sa policy deny</code>  Number of packets denied by an SA policy<br>
<code>sessn thresh</code>  the threshold for the maximum number of sessions<br>
<code>*slow mac</code>   Number of frames whose MAC addresses were slow to resolve<br>
<code>src route</code>   Number of packets dropped because of the filter source route option<br>
<code>syn frag</code>  Number of dropped SYN packets because of a fragmentation<br>
<code>tcp out of seq</code>  Number of TCP segments received whose sequence number is outside the acceptable range<br>
<code>tcp proxy</code>   Number of packets dropped from using a TCP proxy such as the SYN flood protection option or user authentication<br>
<code>teardrop</code>  Number of packets blocked as part of a suspected Teardrop attack<br>
<code>tiny frag</code>   Number of tiny fragmented packets received<br>
<code>trmn drop</code>   Number of packets dropped by traffic management<br>
<code>trmng queue</code>   Number of packets waiting in the queue<br>
<code>udp hdlen err</code>   Number of packets where the IP header is less than the IP header + UDP header.  If IP Total Length is less than 28 bytes (8 bytes UDP header + 20 bytes IP header), it will increase this counter.  This type of traffic is not valid.<br>
<code>udp flood</code>   Number of UDP packets that are counted toward the UDP flood threshold<br>
<code>unknown pak</code>   Any packets with an Ethernet type that the firewall does not recognize. Examples would be Spanning Tree or proprietary Cisco protocols that the firewall does not pass or is capable of reading. When the firewall sees a packet with a Ethernet type it does not recognize, it will drop the packet and increment the &lsquo;unknown pak&rsquo; counter.<br>
<code>url block</code>   Number of HTTP requests that were blocked<br>
<code>winnuke</code>   Number of WinNuke attack packets received<br>
<code>wrong intf</code>  Number of session creation messages sent from a processor module to the master processor module<br>
<code>wrong slot</code>  Number of packets erroneously sent to the wrong processor module<br></p>

<h2>Sources</h2>

<p><a href="http://kb.juniper.net/InfoCenter/index?page=content&amp;id=KB4257">http://kb.juniper.net/InfoCenter/index?page=content&amp;id=KB4257</a><br>
<a href="http://kb.juniper.net/InfoCenter/index?page=content&amp;id=KB4261">http://kb.juniper.net/InfoCenter/index?page=content&amp;id=KB4261</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site to Site VPN tunnel config between a Cisco ASA and a Juniper SSG ScreenOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://tunnelsup.github.io/site-to-site-vpn-tunnel-config-between-a-cisco-asa-and-a-juniper-ssg-screenos/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tunnelsup.github.io/site-to-site-vpn-tunnel-config-between-a-cisco-asa-and-a-juniper-ssg-screenos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below is a config to create a VPN tunnel between a Cisco ASA (Blue side) to a Juniper SSG ScreenOS (Red Side).</p>

<p>Juniper Settings:</p>

<p>ethernet0/0: 22.22.22.22, Untrust
bgroup0: 172.16.22.1, Trust</p>

<p><img src="/images/asasitetosite.jpg" alt="ASA network diagram - IMG" /></p>

<h3>Cisco ASA config (Blue):</h3>

<p>```
!^^^^^^^ ISAKMP (Phase 1) ^^^^^^^!
! must match with the other side in order for Phase 1 to complete.
! Lower policy numbers will likely be used before higher ones.
crypto isakmp policy 5
  authentication pre-share
  encryption aes
  hash sha
  group 2
  lifetime 86400</p>

<p>! Enable ISAKMP on the outside interface
crypto isakmp enable OUTSIDE
! Define the pre-shared-key
tunnel-group 22.22.22.22 type ipsec-l2l
tunnel-group 22.22.22.22 ipsec-attributes
 pre-shared-key sekretk3y</p>

<p>!^^^^^^^ IPSEC (Phase 2) ^^^^^^^!
! Define the interesting traffic in the ACL
access-list ACL-RED-VPN permit ip 192.168.11.0 255.255.255.0 172.16.22.0 255.255.255.0
crypto ipsec transform-set ESP-AES128-SHA esp-aes esp-sha-hmac
! Create a crypto map entry that defines the tunnel
crypto map MAP-OUTSIDE 20 set peer 22.22.22.22
! ACL must be exactly the opposite of the other sides ACL
crypto map MAP-OUTSIDE 20 match address ACL-RED-VPN
! Transform set must match other side identically
crypto map MAP-OUTSIDE 20 set transform-set ESP-AES128-SHA
crypto map MAP-OUTSIDE 20 set security-association lifetime kilobytes 10000
! Apply crypto map to an interface
crypto map MAP-OUTSIDE interface OUTSIDE</p>

<p>!^^^^^^^ Routes and No-NATS ^^^^^^^!
! Point the destination network out the outside interface with a next hop as the default gateway.
route OUTSIDE 172.16.22.0 255.255.255.0 11.11.11.1
! Make sure that the VPN traffic is NOT NATd
access-list ACL-INSIDE-NONAT extended permit ip 192.168.11.0 255.255.255.0 172.16.22.0 255.255.255.0
nat (INSIDE) 0 access-list ACL-INSIDE-NONAT
```</p>

<h3>Juniper SSG-5 ScreenOS config (Red):</h3>

<p>```
! Create a tunnel interface
set interface tunnel.1 zone Untrust
set interface tunnel.1 ip unnumbered interface ethernet0/0</p>

<h1>Create the gateway (IKE settings)</h1>

<h1>note that &ldquo;sec-level standard&rdquo; means the IKE policies will try to use:  pre-g2-3des-sha and pre-g2-aes128-sha</h1>

<p>set ike gateway &ldquo;VPN-GATEWAY&rdquo; ip 11.11.11.11 outgoing-interface ethernet0/0 preshare &ldquo;sekretk3y&rdquo; sec-level standard</p>

<h1>Configure VPN IPSEC settings</h1>

<p>set vpn &ldquo;VPN&rdquo; gateway &ldquo;VPN-GATEWAY&rdquo; replay tunnel idletime 0 proposal &ldquo;nopfs-esp-aes128-sha&rdquo;
set vpn &ldquo;VPN&rdquo; id 1 bind interface tunnel.1
set vpn &ldquo;VPN&rdquo; proxy-id local-ip 172.16.22.0/24 remote-ip 192.168.11.0/24 &ldquo;ANY&rdquo;</p>

<h1>Configure a route for the remote end traffic</h1>

<p>set vrouter trust-vr route 192.168.11.0/24 interface tunnel.1</p>

<h1>Create 2 address book entries and create two policies to permit this traffic</h1>

<p>set address Untrust &ldquo;192.168.11.0/24&rdquo; 192.168.11.0/24
set address Trust &ldquo;172.16.22.0/24&rdquo; 172.16.22.0/24
set policy top from &ldquo;Trust&rdquo; to &ldquo;Untrust&rdquo; &ldquo;172.16.22.0/24&rdquo; &ldquo;192.168.11.0/24&rdquo; &ldquo;ANY&rdquo; Permit log count
set policy top from &ldquo;Untrust&rdquo; to &ldquo;Trust&rdquo; &ldquo;192.168.11.0/24&rdquo; &ldquo;172.16.22.0/24&rdquo; &ldquo;ANY&rdquo; Permit log count
```</p>

<h3>Notes:</h3>

<p>Coming at this from my Cisco background I had to learn some new ways of looking at this.</p>

<p>The traffic that can go over the tunnel is called the proxy-id. It is defined in the vpn settings. You also have to then permit this traffic in a policy between the two zones of your tunnel interface and whatever internal interface you have. In my case my Trust interface was bgroup0.</p>

<h3>Troubleshooting:</h3>

<p>Some show commands to see what&rsquo;s going on:</p>

<p><code>get sa</code></p>

<p><code>get ike gateway</code></p>

<p><code>get event</code></p>

<p>Try creating a packet capture to see what is happening to the packet. With a packet capture you can see what is going on between the two VPN peers, or why your interesting traffic is not making it through the SSG.</p>

<p>```
clear db
set console dbuf
set ffilter src-ip 1.1.1.1 dst-ip 2.2.2.2
debug flow basic</p>

<h1>generate some traffic</h1>

<h1>to see the capture:</h1>

<p>get dbuf stream</p>

<h1>to stop capturing:</h1>

<p>undebug all
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cisco ASA to Juniper ScreenOS to Juniper JunOS Command Reference Cheat Sheet]]></title>
    <link href="http://tunnelsup.github.io/cisco-asa-to-juniper-ssg-command-reference-cheat-sheet/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tunnelsup.github.io/cisco-asa-to-juniper-ssg-command-reference-cheat-sheet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div>
  <style>
     table.ztab1 {
        margin: auto;
        border: 1px solid black;
      }

      table.ztab1 th {
        font-weight: bold;
        background-color: #AAAAAA;
        border-bottom: 2px solid black;
      }

      table.ztab1 th,td {
        padding: 4px 5px;
      }

      table.ztab1 tr:nth-of-type(odd) {
        background-color: #FFFFFF;
      }

      table.ztab1 tr:nth-of-type(even) {
        background-color: #CCCCCC;
      }
  </style>
</div>


<p>Here is a basic reference sheet for looking up equivalent commands between a Cisco ASA and a Juniper ScreenOS (or Netscreen) SSG and a Juniper JunOS SRX firewall.</p>

<table class="ztab1">
<tbody>
<tr>
    <th>Cisco ASA</th>
    <th>Juniper ScreenOS (SSG)</th>
    <th>Juniper JunOS (SRX)</th>
</tr>

<tr>
    <td>show log</td>
    <td>get event</td>
    <td>show log messages<br>
show log messages | last 20 (see the 20 most recent logs)</td>
</tr>

<tr>
    <td>show ip</td>
    <td>get interface</td>
    <td>show interface terse</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show failover</td>
    <td>get nsrp</td>
    <td>show log jsrp<br>
show chassis cluster [status|statistics|interfaces]</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>no failover active</td>
    <td>exec nsrp vsd [vsd] mode backup</td>
    <td>request chassis cluster failover redundancy-group [group] node <node></td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show route</td>
    <td>get route</td>
    <td>show route</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show connections</td>
    <td>get session</td>
    <td>show security flow session</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show clock</td>
    <td>get clock</td>
    <td>show system uptime</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show version (to get uptime)</td>
    <td>get system</td>
    <td>show system uptime</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show running-config</td>
    <td>get config</td>
    <td>show config</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show version (to get serial number)</td>
    <td>get chassis</td>
    <td>show chassis hardware detail</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show access-list</td>
    <td>get policy</td>
    <td>show security policies</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show crypto isakmp sa</td>
    <td>get ike cookie</td>
    <td>show security ike security-associations</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show crypto ipsec sa</td>
    <td><a href="http://kb.juniper.net/InfoCenter/index?page=content&id=KB6134&actp=search">get sa</a></td>
    <td>show security ipsec security-associations</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>clear crypto isakmp sa</td>
    <td>clear ike cookie</td>
    <td>clear security ike security-associations</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>clear crypto ipsec sa</td>
    <td>clear sa</td>
    <td>clear security ipsec security-associations</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show cpu</td>
    <td>get perf cpu</td>
    <td>show chassis routing-engine</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>show proc cpu-usage</td>
    <td></td>
    <td>show system processes extensive</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>show int (for i/o of bytes)</td>
<td> get counter statistics</td>
<td>sh int</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>ssh x.x.x.0 y.y.y.0 inside</td>
<td>set admin manager-ip x.x.x.0 y.y.y.0<br />
set ssh enable</td>
<td>set security zones security-zone TRUST host-inbound-traffic system-services ssh</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>show run [cry isakmp|tunnel-group]?</td>
<td>get ike gateway</td>
<td>show config security ike<br>
show config security ipsec</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>interface Ethernet1<br />
shutdown</td>
<td>set interface ethernet0/0 phy link-down</td>
<td>set interfaces ge-0/0/3 disable</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>interface Ethernet1<br />
no shutdown</td>
<td>unset interface ethernet0/0 phy link-down</td>
<td>delete interfaces ge-0/0/3 disable</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>route outside 1.1.1.0 255.255.255.0 1.1.1.2</td>
<td>set route 1.1.1.0/24 interface bgroup3/0 gateway 1.1.1.2</td>
<td>set routing-options static route 10.10.10.128/25 next-hop 172.16.100.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>logging host INSIDE 1.1.1.1<br />
logging trap notification</td>
<td>set syslog config 1.1.1.1 facilities local5<br />
set syslog src-interface ethernet1/0<br />
set syslog enable</td>
<td>set system syslog source-address 10.14.4.4<br>
set system syslog host 1.1.1.1 any notice</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>ntp server 1.1.1.1 source OUTSIDE</td>
<td>set ntp server 1.1.1.1<br />
set ntp server src-interface ethernet3/0<br />
set clock ntp<br />
exec ntp update</td>
<td>set system ntp server 1.1.1.1 prefer</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>capture CAP1 match ip host 1.1.1.1 host 2.2.2.2</td>
<td>clear db<br />
set console dbuf<br />
set ffilter src-ip 1.1.1.1 dst-ip 2.2.2.2<br />
debug flow basic<br />
<br />
--- OR ---<br />
<br />
snoop filter ip src-ip 1.1.1.1 dst-ip 2.2.2.2 direction both<br />
clear dbuf<br />
snoop</td>
<td>edit security flow traceoptions<br>
set file TSHOOT<br>
set flag basic-datapath<br>
set packet-filter IN-TO-OUT source-prefix 10.1.1.100/32 destination-prefix 10.2.0.3/32
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>show capture CAP1</td>
<td>get dbuf stream</td>
<td>show log TSHOOT</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>clear capture CAP1</td>
<td>undebug all<br />
unset ffilter<br />
<br />
--- OR ---<br />
<br />
snoop filter delete</td>
<td>deactivate security flow traceoptions<br>
delete security flow traceoptions
</td>
</tr>

</tbody>
</table>


<p>Additional reading material regarding Juniper SSG and ScreenOS commands:
<a href="http://www.juniper.net/techpubs/software/screenos/screenos6.2.0/index.html"><a href="http://www.juniper.net/techpubs/software/screenos/screenos6.2.0/index.html">http://www.juniper.net/techpubs/software/screenos/screenos6.2.0/index.html</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
