<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: infosec | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tup/tag/infosec/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-03-05T09:11:49-08:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When is a company ready for a SOC?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/when-is-a-company-ready-for-a-soc/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-25T08:29:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/when-is-a-company-ready-for-a-soc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>More and more companies are deciding to outsource their information security to another company. A Managed Security Service Provider (MSSP) is exactly that, a company that will handle the security of another company. Some MSSPs provide Security Operation Center as a service. This is the fastest and cheapest way to get a SOC. To build a SOC from scratch requires a lot of time, tools, and people. But when is a company ready to get a SOC?</p>

<h3>3 Main Types of Threats</h3>

<p>To understand when a SOC is needed, we must understand what types of threats there are.</p>

<p><strong>Generic</strong> threats are those of the &ldquo;spray and pray&rdquo; type. Imagine a vulnerability scanner, scanning the entire Internet. Imagine global worms like the WCRY (WannaCry) ransomware. These adversaries are just looking for any vulnerability on any systems in any part of the world.</p>

<p><strong>Targeted</strong> threats are attacks against a specific target or software. This may be someone who&rsquo;s goal is to damage a specific company and they will scan/social engineer/attack any open portal the company has exposed to the public. Another type of targeted attack is against specific software, like specifically looking for WordPress sites and attempting to infect those only.</p>

<p><strong>Persistent</strong> threats or otherwise known as Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) is when a highly skilled person or group is using numerous resources to infiltrate a company&rsquo;s network. Picture a tactical team of hackers with a specific mission who has access to unknown vulnerabilities (0 days) or a large pool of manpower, or a large pool of money dedicated all to a single attack. Not many groups have the resources to conduct an APT. Usually when a hacker group is conducting an APT it is for specific reasons such as political.</p>

<h3>Defending Against These Attacks</h3>

<p>Now that we have classified the 3 main types of attacks we can look at ways to defend against each of them.</p>

<p>To defend against a <strong>Generic</strong> attack, an organization should deploy best practices for securing a network. This includes not exposing unneeded ports to the Internet, patching systems, and hardening all devices.</p>

<p>To defend against a <strong>Targeted</strong> attack, an organization should architect the network with security first. This includes segmenting VLANs, denying remote logins to administrator and root, deploying firewalls, IPS units, load balancers, antivirus solutions, and setup loggers and data collectors. Create rules on loggers and data collectors that notify sys admins when a security incident has occurred in the network. In this approach we now consider the network to be fully secured and every effort put in place to stay secured.</p>

<p>To defend against a <strong>Persistent</strong> attack, an organization should be monitoring their logs, snmp traps, netflow, and sometimes full packet captures, 24/7/365 with humans and systems doing the monitoring. That is, the use of a SIEM along with technicians watching the SIEM 24 hours a day. Once an incident is detected, action should then be taken to mitigate the attack. This is called a <strong>SOC</strong>. The theory here is that an APT is usually done by humans who are extremely skilled at exploiting systems, so the defending team needs to also have humans who are skilled at detecting when a system is being exploited. No longer will passive defenses work such as firewalls and IPS units during an APT. Active defenses such as responding to the first sign of an attack are how to defend against this type of attack. Besides having a SOC to detect against these threats, an organization may have additional DFIR teams (Digital Forensics &amp; Incident Response) which can determine the who/what/why/how of an attack.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>Before an organization decides to get a SOC, they should decide what types of attacks they will be facing and why. Everyone is victim to generic attacks, and most companies face a targeted attack on a regular basis. APTs are more rare and doesn&rsquo;t target every organization but takes the most amount of resources to defend against.</p>

<p>Information Security should already be a major focus on a company before they get a SOC. The network should be architected with security first and systems should already be hardened to their best effort. A SOC will spot many security issues and if the admins aren&rsquo;t already capable of securing systems they may not put a lot of focus on recommendations or findings from the SOC. If leadership has already been encouraging admins to focus on security then when SOC alerts come in, the admins should be ready to resolve the issues. It would be a waste of money to create a SOC only to ignore the alerts they report on.</p>

<p>SOCs can also interact with such teams like Malware Investigators, Digital Forensics team, Incident Responders and Threat Intelligence teams. These are obviously even more specialized teams that a company can to make responding to incidents faster, more efficient, and more accurate. These teams can sniff out where the malware came from, who did the attack, what data was leaked from the system and so on. If the organization doesn&rsquo;t care to have this information, and simply rather remove the malware and move on, then these teams aren&rsquo;t needed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Differences between spam and phishing emails]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/differences-between-spam-and-phishing-emails/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-15T14:47:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/differences-between-spam-and-phishing-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes people send me spam mail and tell me they are being phished. Sometimes people ignore phishing emails thinking they are spam. Let&rsquo;s try to understand the differences of the two.</p>

<h2>Definitions</h2>

<p>Spam is:</p>

<blockquote><p>Unsolicited e-mail, often of a commercial nature, sent indiscriminately to multiple mailing lists, individuals, or newsgroups; junk e-mail.</p></blockquote>

<p>Phishing is:</p>

<blockquote><p>To request confidential information over the Internet under false pretenses in order to fraudulently obtain credit card numbers, passwords, or other personal data.</p></blockquote>

<h2>Spam Vs Phishing</h2>

<p>Here are some key differences.</p>

<ul>
<li>Phishing emails are usually targeted to a person. They will often have the person&rsquo;s name already in the email. Spam is more likely to be less personal.</li>
<li>Phishing usually has a sense of urgency. There may be language like &ldquo;free to first 50 people&rdquo;. Spam may not be so immediate.</li>
<li>Phishing usually is trying to get you to click a malicious link or reply to an email (instead of making a phone call).</li>
<li>Phishing links often contain malware or are intended to trick you. Spam links are often to legitimate services and websites that want to sell you a product.</li>
<li>Phishing emails are sent much less frequent than spam.</li>
<li>Phishing emails often are impersonating another company or someone you know. For instance an email that looks like it&rsquo;s from your bank but really not. Spam emails usually don&rsquo;t impersonate or try to trick you into thinking they are someone else.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Samples</h2>

<h4>Sample Spam Email</h4>

<p><img src="/images/spamphish2.png"></p>

<p>First of all this email isn&rsquo;t even to me, it&rsquo;s to someone else and I&rsquo;m in the bcc field. This email looks like it can be sent to thousands of people and not just me. Lastly, the link does in fact take you to a dating site so it&rsquo;s really just an advertisement.</p>

<h4>Sample Phishing Email</h4>

<p><img src="/images/spamphish1.png"></p>

<p>This email looks like it came from Google and I have a new message. This makes it feel like it&rsquo;s directed only to me. But looking at the from address, you can see it&rsquo;s not from Google. Hovering over the links all show that it doesn&rsquo;t take you to a Google website either.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started Cracking Password Hashes with John the Ripper]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/getting-started-cracking-password-hashes/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-08T21:23:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/getting-started-cracking-password-hashes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Want to get started with password cracking and not sure where to begin? In this post we&rsquo;ll explore how to get started with it.</p>

<p>Most systems don&rsquo;t store passwords on them. Instead they store hashes of passwords and when authentication takes place, the password is hashes and if the hashes match authentication is successful. Different systems store password hashes in different ways depending on the encryption used.</p>

<p>Password hash cracking usually consists of taking a wordlist, hashing each word and comparing it against the hash you&rsquo;re trying to crack. This is a variation of a dictionary attack because wordlists often are composed of not just dictionary words but also passwords from public password dumps. This type of cracking becomes difficult when hashes are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salt_(cryptography">salted</a>).</p>

<p>The tool we are going to use to do our password hashing in this post is called <strong>John the Ripper</strong>. John is a great tool because it&rsquo;s free, fast, and can do both wordlist style attacks and brute force attacks. A brute force attack is where the program will cycle through every possible character combination until it has found a match.</p>

<h2>Setup</h2>

<p>To get setup we&rsquo;ll need some password hashes and John the Ripper.</p>

<h4>Sample Password Hashes</h4>

<p>A group called KoreLogic used to hold DEFCON competitions to see how well people could crack password hashes. Their contest files are still posted on their site and it offers a great sample set of hashes to begin with.</p>

<p>Download the <a href="http://contest-2012.korelogic.com/">password hash file bundle</a> from the KoreLogic 2012 DEFCON challenge.
Or use this <a href="/images/cmiyc_2012_password_hash_files.tar.bz2">mirror</a>.</p>

<p>Extract the file using this linux command:</p>

<p><code>
tar jxf cmiyc_2012_password_hash_files.tar.bz2
</code></p>

<p>This expands into 19 different hashdumps including <code>des</code>, <code>md5</code>, and <code>ntlm</code> type encryption. Each of the 19 files contains thousands of password hashes. This should be a great data set to test our cracking capabilities on.</p>

<h4>John the Ripper</h4>

<p>Next we&rsquo;ll need the cracking tool itself. If you&rsquo;re using Kali Linux, this tool is already installed. Download <a href="http://www.openwall.com/john/">John the Ripper</a> here. In my case I&rsquo;m going to download the free version <code>John the Ripper 1.8.0 (sources, tar.gz, 5.2 MB)</code>.</p>

<p>Once downloaded, extract it with the following linux command:</p>

<p><code>
tar zxvf john-1.8.0.tar.gz
</code></p>

<p>Then follow the instructions in docs/INSTALL to complete the install.</p>

<h4>Getting a Wordlist</h4>

<p>We&rsquo;ll need a good wordlist to go through to see if any passwords in it, match our hashes.</p>

<ul>
<li>A basic word list containing 3,559 words can be found bundled in the John the Ripper tarball in the run dir. This is a list of the most common passwords seen in public hash dumps.</li>
<li>If using Kali linux, a good size wordfile is located at <code>/usr/share/wordlists/rockyou.txt.gz</code>. Unzip it with <code>gunzip</code> and you&rsquo;ve got a good wordfile to workwith.</li>
<li>A large word list containing 1,493,677,782 words can be found at <a href="https://crackstation.net/buy-crackstation-wordlist-password-cracking-dictionary.htm">crackstation</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>The size word list you need depends on your needs. If you have a large hashdump, chances are even cracking 5% of the hashes will result in a victory, which may get you admin access. But if you have a only one password hash, you&rsquo;ll need 100% success rate and probably need a bigger wordlist.</p>

<h2>Basic John Usage</h2>

<p>Use John to begin the cracking with this command:</p>

<p><code>
$ john hashes-3.des.txt
Loaded 10297 password hashes with 3741 different salts (descrypt, traditional crypt(3) [DES 32/32])
</code></p>

<p>This simple command does the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>Detected there are 10,297 password hashes in the file and their salts.</li>
<li>Auto detected the passwords were DES encrypted</li>
<li>Will first attempt single crack mode</li>
<li>Will then attempt to use the built in wordlist (most common passwords) to crack passwords</li>
<li>Will then go into incremental mode</li>
</ul>


<h2>Checking Status</h2>

<p>While John the Ripper is running, press any key (like enter) to see a status output. Or to check from another terminal you can run <code>john --status</code>.  The output looks like this:</p>

<p><code>
DES cracking speed: 94g 0:01:08:34 74% 2/3 0.02284g/s 2784p/s 97648c/s 269491C/s day?..Hal?
1                   2   3          4   5   6          7       8        9         10
</code></p>

<p>Here is what each section means:</p>

<ol>
<li>Type of encryption it is trying to crack with</li>
<li>Number of successful password guesses</li>
<li>Time elapsed since started</li>
<li>Percent completed for that pass</li>
<li>Current pass / number of passes total</li>
<li>g/s = successful guesses per second</li>
<li>p/s = passwords tested per second</li>
<li>c/s = crypts (password hashes) computed per second</li>
<li>C/s = crypts tested per second (in versions below 1.8.0 this was &ldquo;c/s&rdquo;)</li>
<li>The current word it&rsquo;s trying.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Passes/Modes</h2>

<p>John has three modes to attempt to crack hashes. If you do not indicate the mode, all 3 will be used and you will see <code>x/3</code> in your status output indicating which mode it&rsquo;s on.</p>

<p>See <a href="http://www.openwall.com/john/doc/MODES.shtml">http://www.openwall.com/john/doc/MODES.shtml</a> for detailed description of each mode.</p>

<h4>(1) Single Crack</h4>

<p>This mode attempts to mangle the username and try it as the password. Example: if the username was &ldquo;jackson&rdquo; it would try the following passwords:</p>

<blockquote><p>jackson <br>
JACKSON <br>
jackson1 <br>
j-ackson <br>
Jackson= <br>
jacks0n <br></p></blockquote>

<p>It tries hundreds of variations of the username. It tries this password on all hashes in your file so the more usernames you give it, the greater chance of it finding something in the single crack mode.</p>

<p>This is a great mode to start with because it&rsquo;s the fastest and sometimes works wonderfully.</p>

<p>To just use this mode do the following:</p>

<p><code>
john --single hashes-3.des.txt
</code></p>

<h4>(2) Wordlist Mode</h4>

<p>In this mode, John is using a wordlist to hash each word and compare the hash with the password hash. If you do not indicate a wordlist, John will use the one it comes bundled with which has about 3,500 words which are the most common passwords seen in password dumps.</p>

<p>To use try just the wordlist mode do the following:</p>

<p><code>
john --wordlist=password.lst hashes-3.des.txt
</code></p>

<h4>(3) Incremental</h4>

<p>Attempts a brute force style attack, trying every combination of characters possible. This type of attempt will never complete because it will just keep trying higher and higher password lengths.</p>

<p>To try just the incremental mode, do this command:</p>

<p><code>
john --incremental hashes-3.des.txt
</code></p>

<h2>Word mangling rules</h2>

<p>John has the ability to take a wordlist and mangle the words in it to try variations of that word. It will add numbers to the end of the word and try replacing letters with numbers and adding other random symbols. So if the word list contains the word <code>jackson</code>, with <code>rules</code> turned on it would try each of these plus hundreds more.</p>

<blockquote><p>jackson <br>
JACKSON <br>
jackson1 <br>
j-ackson <br>
Jackson= <br>
jacks0n <br></p></blockquote>

<p>By simply enabling <code>--rules</code> when invoking John, the mangling rules applied are usually decent. However, you can modify the config file to alter the way the mangling is done. Read here for further information on how to do that:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.openwall.com/john/doc/RULES.shtml">http://www.openwall.com/john/doc/RULES.shtml</a></p>

<p>Additionally you can see what others have used for rules like KoreLogic:</p>

<p><a href="http://contest-2010.korelogic.com/rules.html">http://contest-2010.korelogic.com/rules.html</a></p>

<h2>Final Example</h2>

<p>To use a larger word list, with DES encryption only, and rule mangling turned on, use the following:</p>

<p><code>
john --format:descrypt --wordlist=crackstation-human-only.txt --rules hashes-3.des.txt
</code></p>

<p>The best way to get John to run in the background is using the standard linux <code>screen</code> command.</p>

<h2>Resources</h2>

<p><a href="http://www.openwall.com/john/doc/">http://www.openwall.com/john/doc/</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.openwall.com/john/doc/EXAMPLES.shtml">http://www.openwall.com/john/doc/EXAMPLES.shtml</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips For Attending a Security Conference]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tips-for-attending-a-security-conference/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-27T11:32:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/tips-for-attending-a-security-conference</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re in the InfoSec industry and haven&rsquo;t attended a security conference, you simply aren&rsquo;t taking your career seriously. Attending one will inspire you and motivate you to learn new things, meet new people, and find new solutions to your problems. There are so many conferences now that there is about 2-5 every month! A realistic goal could be to attend one security conference a year.</p>

<h2>Types of Conferences</h2>

<p>There are two different types of conferences: <strong>community driven</strong> and <strong>vendor driven</strong>. Community driven conferences are like <a href="https://defcon.org/">DefCon</a> and BSides. These have speakers from the InfoSec community and very little corporate vendor booths. Vendor driven conferences are like <a href="http://www.rsaconference.com/">RSA Conf</a> or <a href="http://www.ciscolive.com/us/">Cisco Live</a> which has a massive vendor floor and almost all the talks are given to vendors to either pitch their solutions or talk on something else.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re in a management or in a leadership position, you may prefer the vendor based ones to learn what solutions vendors have today that can solve your problems.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re highly technical then a community based one will help you solve problems you may be facing by getting in the weeds and getting technical with others.</p>

<h2>Tips for Getting the Most Out of a Conference</h2>

<h4>Meet people</h4>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">One of the biggest reasons I go to security conferences and meetups. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/infosec?src=hash">#infosec</a> <a href="https://t.co/Y0HB9dtchO">pic.twitter.com/Y0HB9dtchO</a></p>&mdash; Jack Rhysider (@TunnelsUp) <a href="https://twitter.com/TunnelsUp/status/730938951696060416">May 13, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="https://www.tunnelsup.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Meeting people who have the same problems or passions than I do is the most important thing on my agenda when attending these conferences. Finding new people to share ideas with, solve your problems, or teach you how to improve is a resource you can use for years. Having a secret weapon of someone you can ask tough questions to outside of work will make you look like an endless fountain of information.</p>

<p>A few ways to meet people:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you&rsquo;re active on Twitter, find out which of your tweeps are attending and make time to meet them.</li>
<li>Join a team event with people you don&rsquo;t know, such as a workshop or contest.</li>
<li>Be a speaker! You&rsquo;ll have many people wanting to talk to you after.</li>
<li>Ask a ton of questions. See something you aren&rsquo;t familiar with? Don&rsquo;t be afraid to ask what it is or how it works. See someone else asking smart questions? Talk to them about your thoughts on the questions.</li>
<li>Go to after parties where the conversations keep going.</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://twitter.com/irongeek_adc">Adrian Crenshaw</a> from <a href="http://www.irongeek.com/">IronGeek</a> has attended dozens of conferences. When asked about what he suggests doing at conference he wrote:</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t neglect hallway con.</p></blockquote>

<p>He&rsquo;s suggesting to talk to people in line, or in the hallway, or in the chair next to you as you wait for a talk to start. Getting to know people at these conference is an extremely valuable resource.</p>

<h4>Talks</h4>

<p>Talks are the main event of any conference. Often there are multiple talks going on at once so it&rsquo;s a good idea to get the schedule before arriving so you can plan your day.</p>

<p>But you don&rsquo;t have to attend the talks! In 2015 there were over <a href="/online-security-conferences/">50 security conferences</a> that recorded their talks and posted them free online. If your conference is recording them, feel free to skip the live ones and just watch them later.</p>

<p>If you watch a talk you enjoyed or agreed with, follow that speaker on Twitter. There is a huge Twitter community of InfoSec professionals and they&rsquo;d be happy to answer any follow up questions you have later.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t like the talk 5 minutes in? Don&rsquo;t be embarrassed to leave. It&rsquo;s your time and you should do whatever you want. This kind of makes it hard when you are attending conferences with friends or a group because if you separate mid talk it&rsquo;s hard to find each other.</p>

<h4>Watch your electronics</h4>

<p>If you&rsquo;re going to a hacker con such as DefCon, make sure to leave your work and personal electronics at home. Bring a burner phone and burner laptop. Stuff you won&rsquo;t care too badly about if it gets hacked into. Bring a pad and paper if you want to take notes.</p>

<h4>Participate</h4>

<p>Some conferences have workshops, villages, contests, mini-breakout sessions, and more. If there is a contest, try competing. Your goal isn&rsquo;t to win, it&rsquo;s simply to not get last place. If you can achieve that, you&rsquo;re a winner. As you participate in these activities, you&rsquo;ll learn new skills and meet new friends. Doing hands on activities will likely help you learn a lot more than listening to a talk.</p>

<h4>Vendors</h4>

<p>Talk to vendors you don&rsquo;t know and find out what they do. Often I learn that they solve problems I didn&rsquo;t even know existed. This kind of information can help broaden your understanding of the InfoSec space. Often, vendors will give out free things like tshirts and flashlights you can take back for your friends in the office. Take as much of this as you want.</p>

<h4>Secret stuff</h4>

<p>Some conferences have hidden stuff that is hard to get into. Often there are exclusive parties for customers or friends. Once, I found a hidden party through a trick door inside a phone booth. There are sometimes even hidden talks. DefCon has a thing called SkyTalks which are smaller rooms, and not recorded. This intimate setting allows speakers to tell a little more than they probably should.</p>

<h4><a href="http://www.securitybsides.com/">BSides</a></h4>

<p>Many of the major conferences have smaller <a href="http://www.securitybsides.com/">BSides</a> conferences in the same city near the same time as the larger one. These smaller BSides conferences are a lot cheaper to attend and are much more community oriented. They are definitely worth checking out and there may even be one in your town.</p>

<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>I hope some of these tips are helpful to you and I hope to see you at a future conference. Do you have any more tips that are helpful for attending conferences? Leave a comment below to let us all know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who Makes up a Computer Security Incident Response Team]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/who-makes-up-an-computer-security-incident-response-team/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-25T10:50:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/who-makes-up-an-computer-security-incident-response-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The incident response team is who is engaged when an network security incident has occurred in your network. There are two types of IR teams, SWAT style and dedicated.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/hacks4pancakes">Lesley Carhart</a> defines an IR team goal as:</p>

<blockquote><p>The goal of an incident response team is to reduce the time and money lost due to an incident.</p></blockquote>

<h2>SWAT Teams</h2>

<p>In smaller organizations, where security incidents are not very common or severe, a SWAT team works best. This is simply an adhoc group of people who are most familiar with the impacted systems. Such as the system admins and network admins. Once the incident is contained, these people go back to their normal jobs.</p>

<h2>Dedicated Teams</h2>

<p>In a dedicated incident response team, the roles are more specifically defined. This team is also sometimes known as a Computer Incident Response Team (CIRT), or Computer Security Incident Response Team (CSIRT).</p>

<p>Roles of a CSIRT:
<img src="/images/dfirteam.png" alt="CIRT Team Roles" /></p>

<h4>SOC Monitoring Team</h4>

<p>While not exactly part of the IR team, the security operations center is usually where security incidents are first detected. This team will monitor logs and events 24/7 and hunt for threats in the network. They will report the incidents they find to the IR team.</p>

<h4>Incident Handlers</h4>

<p>It&rsquo;s difficult to work towards resolving an incident while also giving reports to leadership or other stake holders. The incident handler makes sure the proper teams are engaged to respond to the incident, and they also give updates to leadership and other teams who may be interested in knowing about the the incident status. They may join conference calls to relay information to different teams.</p>

<h4>Malware Investigator</h4>

<p>Sometimes an AV scan can&rsquo;t find the malware on a system. Malware investigators will find the malware and possibly extract it to further study it. They are very familiar with what is normal on a system compared to what is not normal. They also will be able to tell what activity the malware has, such as spreading or any command and control it may be trying to do.</p>

<h4>Digital Forensics</h4>

<p>This team will try to find more information about what the system experienced during the incident. Did records get deleted or moved? Who accessed this system? What actions did users take on that system? Did they leave anything behind, like keyloggers or rootkits? What connections did it made? Knowing these things may be important to determining how wide spread the incident is or the extent of the damage.</p>

<p>In the case of a PCI certified organization getting breached, the organization must be able to replay the attack so they can prove they understand how the attacker accessed the network. A digital forensics specialist will help significantly with this type of investigation.</p>

<h4>Threat Intelligence Team</h4>

<p>This team will get to know who the adversary is, what their motive was, what their target was, and what techniques they used. Finding who did the attack may be helpful for carrying out legal responses to the attacker. Finding out what their motive is will help the risk manager know why we are a target for attacks. Finding out what techniques were used will help the SOC identify future attacks. This team can spend 6 months or longer investigating a single incident to feel confident with the assessment results. They will use all the evidence the malware and forensics teams find, as well as work with other teams to collect as much evidence as possible to create their assessment. They will often use Open Source Intelligence (OSINT) to research adversaries, malware history, APT reports, etc.</p>

<h4>IT Staff</h4>

<p>Often, the best person to spot something being abnormal is the person who owns that system. They are also usually the most familiar with that system and can help with any troubleshooting or information gathering that may need to be done on the system.</p>

<h4>Security Engineer</h4>

<p>Security engineers and architects should be working towards making the network more secure by reviewing past incidents and then putting configurations in place to protect against future attacks. Once an organization is hit once from a specific attack, the organization should learn what that is and put safeguards in place to not be hit by that same attack again. This is where security engineering can protect the network proactivly.</p>

<h4>Pen Testers</h4>

<p>If an attack supposedly got int through a non-secure website, a pen tester can try to recreate that attack to see if it is possible. Sometimes the system owners believe their application is secure and it takes a pen tester to show them it isn&rsquo;t. Also, a pen tester can learn from the adversary what type of attack was conducted and attempt to use that attack on other systems to see if they are vulnerable too.</p>

<h4>Leadership</h4>

<p>The leadership team is one of the most important because without proper leadership, the security team will be limited and without vision or direction. Proper buy in from leadership is crucial in order for the rest of the organization to respect and see value in the IR team. Leadership may also be called in to make decisions that may impact business such as taking down key servers that are infected which may stop business for hours or days. It&rsquo;s also important for leadership to take action on communicating breaches to customers. Leadership will also decide the course of action when responding to an attack. This may be calling the police, or FBI, or even attacking back.</p>

<h4>Various Other Teams</h4>

<p>Teams such as HR, Legal, and Branding all make up the IR team if there are incidents that impact these parts of the organization. Security can impact the entire organization and these teams are specialized in their own areas and should be aware of problems in those areas. These teams can also help navigate how to resolve some incidents such as firing an employee which was caught showing malicious activity inside the network.</p>

<h2>Further Information</h2>

<p>To learn more about this topic, check out this free 3 hour long workshop on youtube by <a href="https://twitter.com/hacks4pancakes">Lesley Carhart</a> called <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LYGi12N6oFQ">Building an Incident Response Program</a></strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
