<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ironport | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tup/tag/ironport/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-05-03T11:52:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Configure Ironport to act as a smarthost]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/configure-ironport-to-act-as-a-smarthost/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T09:41:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/configure-ironport-to-act-as-a-smarthost</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ironport Email Appliance (ESA) can act as a smarthost to relay email outbound to the internet. The trick to doing this is to have two interfaces on the Ironport, one acting as incoming from the internet and one acting as incoming from the exchange server. Here is how to configure the internal interface to relay mail from exchange.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Click on &lsquo;Add Listener&rsquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Name the listener &lsquo;OutboundMail&rsquo;</p></li>
<li><p>For &lsquo;Type of Listener&rsquo; select &lsquo;Private&rsquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Submit this page</p></li>
<li><p>Click &lsquo;HAT&rsquo; link for the new &lsquo;OutboundMail&rsquo; listener</p></li>
<li><p>Click on &lsquo;RELAYLIST&rsquo;</p></li>
<li><p>Click on &lsquo;Add Sender&rsquo; and add the IP address(es) of your mail servers to this sender group.  This allows only the IP addresses that you specify to relay, and ensures that they are treated as outgoing senders.</p></li>
<li><p>Submit this page</p></li>
<li><p>Commit the changes</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Initial configuration of a Cisco ASA and Ironport WSA using WCCP]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/initial-configuration-of-a-cisco-asa-and-ironport-wsa-using-wccp/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/initial-configuration-of-a-cisco-asa-and-ironport-wsa-using-wccp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we are going to set up a Cisco ASA firewall to send WCCP (port 80) web inspection traffic to a Cisco Ironport WSA (Web Security Appliance).</p>

<p>Suppose the following:</p>

<p>Ironport WSA IP address: 192.168.5.55</p>

<p>Inside IP of ASA firewall: 192.168.5.1</p>

<p>Inside IP address range: 192.168.0.0/16</p>

<h3>Cisco ASA firewall configuration</h3>

<p>```
! Define the Ironport IP Address in an ACL
access-list ACL-IRONPORT-WSA extended permit ip host 192.168.5.55 any</p>

<p>! Define what traffic should be inspected
access-list ACL-WEBPROXY-TRAFFIC extended permit tcp 192.168.0.0 255.255.0.0 any eq www</p>

<p>! Apply the WCCP configuration
wccp web-cache redirect-list ACL-WEBPROXY-TRAFFIC group-list ACL-IRONPORT-WSA
wccp interface INSIDE web-cache redirect in
```</p>

<h3>Ironport Configuration</h3>

<p>Navigate to <code>Network</code> &ndash;> <code>Transparent Redirection</code></p>

<p>Make the type WCCP v2 Router</p>

<p>Add a service with a name of <code>WEB_CACHE</code>, a router IP of <code>192.168.5.1</code> (ASA Inside IP) and port <code>80</code> (Standard).</p>

<p>At this point you can do a &lsquo;show wccp&rsquo; on the ASA and you should see &ldquo;Total Packets Redirected&rdquo; rising. From within the Ironport go to <code>Reporting</code> &ndash;> <code>Overview</code> and you should see statistics of what traffic is now flowing through the Ironport.</p>

<h3>Troubleshooting techniques:</h3>

<ul>
    <li>Verify basic connectivity. Check interface IP addresses. Verify network access between both ASA and Ironport.</li>
    <li>Show commands on ASA: show wccp</li>
    <li>Debug commands on firewall: debug wccp packet, debug wccp events</li>
    <li>Verify the ports caught in the traffic ACL are the same as the ports used for WCCP and there's a listener (service) on Ironport to interpret them.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MX Record problem: Reverse DNS does not match SMTP Banner]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/mx-record-problem-reverse-dns-does-not-match-smtp-banner/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/mx-record-problem-reverse-dns-does-not-match-smtp-banner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was given a problem that our Cisco Ironport was not accepting email from outside people sending mail to inside people (backstory: this occurred right after we moved our Ironport to a different location). I looked in Ironport and spotted a lot of messages failing to be delivered. Specifically the error in Ironport was:
<code>Message 1006902 aborted: Receiving aborted</code></p>

<p>I spent a long time doing packet captures to try to troubleshoot and determined the remote end was sending a reset which made me think this is the sender&rsquo;s problem and not mine. However I was wrong.</p>

<p>The next thing I checked was the MX Record at <a href="http://mxtoolbox.com">MXToolbox.com</a> (a great site for looking up DNS records and stuff). Specifically the SMTP test showed this:</p>

<p><img src="/images/mxfail.png" alt="MX failing - IMG" /></p>

<p>Specifically I didn&rsquo;t like seeing this warning:
<strong>SMTP Reverse DNS Mismatch &mdash;&ndash; Warning &ndash; Reverse DNS does not match SMTP Banner</strong>
and
<strong>SMTP TLS &mdash;&ndash; Warning &ndash; Does not support TLS</strong></p>

<p>But what does that mean? I specifically wanted to know what two strings are being compared that resulted in a mismatch. Well in the case above the two strings it was comparing were <strong>***********************</strong> and <strong>mail3.example.com</strong>. For some reason this took me a long time to realize the ********************* was the banner&hellip; You can see it in the image above after 220.</p>

<p>Looking around on the internet it turns out that our Cisco ASA we have in front of the Ironport has <code>inspect esmtp</code> turned on (which is on by default).</p>

<p>Issue the following commands to turn off the inspect:</p>

<p><code>
policy-map global_policy
 class inspection_default
  no inspect esmtp
</code></p>

<p>Upon turning that inspect off the issue immediately cleared up and the results were this:</p>

<p><img src="/images/mxpass.png" alt="MX passing - IMG" /></p>

<p>Mail was then flowing into the Ironport properly and being delivered as expected. Looking back at the problem if I would have looked at the logs in the ASA I would have seen these syslogs:</p>

<p><code>%ASA-4-108004: ESMTP Classification: Dropped connection for ESMTP Request from outside:75.75.75.75/35314 to DMZ:10.0.25.101/25; matched Class 4: header line length gt 998</code></p>

<p><code>%ASA-4-507003: tcp flow from outside:75.75.75.75/35314 to PUBLIC_DMZ:10.0.25.101/25 terminated by inspection engine, reason - inspector disconnected, dropped packet.</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
