<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: asa | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tup/tag/asa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-02T12:55:45-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cisco ASA command to show listening ports]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-command-to-show-listening-ports/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-29T15:05:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-command-to-show-listening-ports</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you wish there was a <code>netstat</code> command for a Cisco ASA? Are you looking to see what ports the ASA has open and is listening on? Try this command:</p>

<p>```
ASA5506# sh asp table socket</p>

<p>Protocol  Socket    State      Local Address        Foreign Address
SSL       0001ebf8  LISTEN     172.16.3.1:443       0.0.0.0:<em>
TCP       000216f8  LISTEN     172.16.3.1:22        0.0.0.0:</em>
TCP       370c1d68  LISTEN     99.99.99.99:22       0.0.0.0:*
TCP       3712d678  ESTAB      172.16.3.1:22        172.16.2.3:50233
```</p>

<p>This command displays all of the ports that are open and established on the ASA.</p>

<p>The <code>state</code> indicates whether the port is listening or established.</p>

<p>The <code>local address</code> says which IP it&rsquo;s listening on. In the example above, 99.99.99.99 is the outside interface and the 172.16.3.1 is the inside interface.</p>

<p>The <code>foreign address</code> will show up when someone connects to that port. In this case I was ssh&rsquo;d into the firewall coming from 172.16.2.3.</p>

<p>The output above should be a direct reflection of the <code>ssh</code>, <code>telnet</code>, and <code>http</code> commands in the ASA.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to show and clear user sessions on a Cisco ASA]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/how-to-show-and-clear-user-sessions-on-a-cisco-asa/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-18T16:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/how-to-show-and-clear-user-sessions-on-a-cisco-asa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you need to disconnect someone&rsquo;s ssh session to a Cisco ASA. This may be needed because users haven&rsquo;t logged out properly and have taken up all the sessions allowed.</p>

<h2>Check Usage Limits</h2>

<p>You can check usage limits by seeing how many sessions the ASA <em>thinks</em> are connected.</p>

<p><code>
FWL1# show resource usage resource ssh
Resource                 Current        Peak      Limit        Denied Context
SSH Server                     5           5          5           109 System
</code></p>

<p>In this case the ASA can only connect 5 years and it thinks there are 5 sessions open and therefore it cannot connect any more.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a bug that doesn&rsquo;t properly release sessions from the ASA. <a href="https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCsm68097">https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCsm68097</a></p>

<h2>Show current ssh sessions</h2>

<p>To display all ssh sessions connected run this command.</p>

<p>```
FWL1# show ssh sessions                      <br/>
SID Client IP       Version Mode Encryption Hmac     State            Username
0   10.1.1.21       2.0     IN   aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   james</p>

<pre><code>                        OUT  aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   james
</code></pre>

<p>2   10.1.1.22       2.0     IN   aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   frank</p>

<pre><code>                        OUT  aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   frank
</code></pre>

<p>3   10.1.1.20       2.0     IN   aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   henry</p>

<pre><code>                        OUT  aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   henry
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Disconnect user</h2>

<p>If you want to disconnect user henry, find the SID and use this command:</p>

<p><code>
FWL1# ssh disconnect 3
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starter Config for Cisco ASA 5506]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/starter-config-for-cisco-asa-5506/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-16T22:46:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/starter-config-for-cisco-asa-5506</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Are you trying to set up a Cisco ASA 5506 for the first time and want to see a sample config to get you started? Well then here&rsquo;s a good template to get started with. A 5506 is often intended for a small office or home office. In our scenario there is no DMZ and we are connecting to a cable modem using DHCP.</p>

<p>Here is a basic template you can use to get started with quickly. These commands will work with any ASA version 8.3 and up. I would say this will work with any ASA version 7.2 and up, except the NAT command and DHCP commands would not work.
```
!
hostname My-Firewall
enable password mysekretspecialenablepassw0rd
!
interface GigabitEthernet1/1
 nameif OUTSIDE
 security-level 0
 ip address dhcp setroute
!
interface GigabitEthernet1/2
 nameif INSIDE
 security-level 100
 ip address 192.168.55.1 255.255.255.0
!
interface GigabitEthernet1/3
 shutdown
 no nameif
 no security-level
 no ip address
!
interface GigabitEthernet1/4
 shutdown
 no nameif
 no security-level
 no ip address
!
interface GigabitEthernet1/5
 shutdown
 no nameif
 no security-level
 no ip address
!
interface GigabitEthernet1/6
 shutdown
 no nameif
 no security-level
 no ip address
!
interface GigabitEthernet1/7
 shutdown
 no nameif
 no security-level
 no ip address
!
interface GigabitEthernet1/8
 shutdown
 no nameif
 no security-level
 no ip address
!
interface Management1/1
 management-only
 no nameif
 no security-level
 no ip address
!
ftp mode passive
clock timezone PDT -7
object-group network OBJ-INSIDE-NETWORKS
 network-object 192.168.55.0 255.255.255.0
 network-object 192.168.56.0 255.255.255.0
access-list ACL-OUTSIDE-IN extended permit icmp any any echo-reply
access-list ACL-OUTSIDE-IN extended deny ip any any
access-list ACL-INSIDE-IN extended permit ip object-group OBJ-INSIDE-NETWORKS any
access-list ACL-INSIDE-IN extended deny ip any any
pager lines 24
logging enable
logging timestamp
logging monitor notifications
logging buffered notifications
logging asdm informational
mtu OUTSIDE 1500
mtu INSIDE 1500
icmp unreachable rate-limit 1 burst-size 1
no asdm history enable
arp timeout 14400
no arp permit-nonconnected
nat (INSIDE,OUTSIDE) source dynamic any interface description Main PAT
access-group ACL-OUTSIDE-IN in interface OUTSIDE
access-group ACL-INSIDE-IN in interface INSIDE</p>

<p>route INSIDE 192.168.56.0 255.255.255.0 192.168.55.2 1
timeout xlate 3:00:00
timeout pat-xlate 0:00:30
timeout conn 1:00:00 half-closed 0:10:00 udp 0:02:00 icmp 0:00:02
timeout sunrpc 0:10:00 h323 0:05:00 h225 1:00:00 mgcp 0:05:00 mgcp-pat 0:05:00
timeout sip 0:30:00 sip_media 0:02:00 sip-invite 0:03:00 sip-disconnect 0:02:00
timeout sip-provisional-media 0:02:00 uauth 0:05:00 absolute
timeout tcp-proxy-reassembly 0:01:00
timeout floating-conn 0:00:00
user-identity default-domain LOCAL
aaa authentication ssh console LOCAL
aaa authentication enable console LOCAL
aaa authentication http console LOCAL
no snmp-server location
no snmp-server contact
service sw-reset-button
crypto ipsec security-association pmtu-aging infinite
crypto ca trustpool policy
telnet timeout 5
no ssh stricthostkeycheck
ssh 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 INSIDE
ssh timeout 60
ssh key-exchange group dh-group1-sha1
console timeout 0
dhcpd auto_config OUTSIDE
!
dhcpd address 192.168.55.50-192.168.55.150 INSIDE
dhcpd enable INSIDE
!
threat-detection basic-threat
threat-detection statistics access-list
no threat-detection statistics tcp-intercept
dynamic-access-policy-record DfltAccessPolicy
username johndoe password oVIhyCAOOHIOur6g encrypted privilege 15
!
class-map inspection_default
 match default-inspection-traffic
!
!
policy-map type inspect dns preset_dns_map
 parameters
  message-length maximum client auto
  message-length maximum 512
policy-map global_policy
 class inspection_default
  inspect dns preset_dns_map
  inspect ftp
  inspect h323 h225
  inspect h323 ras
  inspect rsh
  inspect rtsp
  inspect esmtp
  inspect sqlnet
  inspect skinny<br/>
  inspect sunrpc
  inspect xdmcp
  inspect sip<br/>
  inspect netbios
  inspect tftp
  inspect ip-options
!
service-policy global_policy global
prompt hostname context
```</p>

<h3>Breakdown of commands</h3>

<ol>
<li><p>Set the interface configuration. In this template Gig1/1 is OUTSIDE and Gig1/2 is INSIDE. The OUTSIDE route is not only DHCP but I want it to be the default route. That&rsquo;s why the <code>setroute</code> command is there. The INSIDE interface has a static IP. Security level on the outside or untrusted network should always be higher than the inside or trusted network.</p></li>
<li><p>Create a NAT. In the template above there&rsquo;s only one PAT. This is important so all outgoing traffic can go through the firewall and get NAT&rsquo;d to the outside IP of the firewall.</p></li>
<li><p>Set any routes. In the example above we have the 192.168.56.0/24 network on the inside so we made a route for it. If there are no extra networks on the inside then we don&rsquo;t need this.</p></li>
<li><p>Set the ACLs. This is important to configure so it stops all incoming attacks to your network. The example above permits only ICMP (ping) replies and then denies everything else on the outside interface. Because a firewall is stateful, it will remember and permit any traffic originating from the inside and permit it back in. Essentially the template configuration let&rsquo;s you go out to the internet, but doesn&rsquo;t let any unwanted traffic in. I like to set the inside interface to only permit what I know exists inside my network. This is why the inside ACL permits only the inside networks.</p></li>
<li><p>Create a username and set the AAA configuration. In this case we created a johndoe username and set the <code>ssh</code> and <code>aaa</code> commands. This creates a user, configures logon settings, and permits ssh capabilities to the firewalls. You may want to lookup how to set up ssh for your ASA since you need to generate keys to do so.</p></li>
<li><p>Create a DHCP server (Optional). If you need to dynamically give DHCP addresses to hosts connecting to the ASA you can configure DHCP on the ASA to handle this. These commands are in the template. The <code>auto_config</code> command should pull any domain info and DNS servers out of the outside interface that uses DHCP to get it&rsquo;s information. If it doesn&rsquo;t then you can manually set the DNS server using <code>dhcpd dns 4.2.2.2</code>.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cisco ASA TCP Randomization Issue]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-tcp-randomization-issue/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-29T23:21:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-tcp-randomization-issue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may sometimes see this syslog message from a Cisco ASA:</p>

<p><code>%ASA-4-419002: Received duplicate TCP SYN from in_interface : src_address / src_port to out_interface : dest_address / dest_port with different initial sequence number.</code></p>

<p>I see this a lot on VPN firewalls where packets are dropped due to the sequence numbers not being correct in TCP.  This happens when the ASA randomizes the TCP sequence numbers and another device is also performing the same randomization of the TCP sequence numbers.</p>

<p>One way to bypass this is to disable TCP Sequence Number randomization on the ASA.  This can be done on a selective basis.  (NOTE:  You may need this as well as Option 19 permissions if you are putting BGP through the firewall).</p>

<p>Here is a sample conf to disable TCP randomization for a specific subnet:</p>

<p>```
access-list ACL-SEQUENCE-NUMBER extended permit tcp vpn-ip-pool any
access-list ACL-SEQUENCE-NUMBER extended permit tcp any vpn-ip-pool</p>

<p>class-map CM-SEQUENCE-NUMBER
  match access-list ACL-SEQUENCE-NUMBER</p>

<p>policy-map global_policy
class CM-SEQUENCE-NUMBER
  set connection random-sequence-number disable
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cisco ASA Best Practices]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-best-practices/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-15T20:45:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-best-practices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are a list of best practices that can be applied to a Cisco ASA.</p>

<h2>Keep it up to date</h2>

<p>Upgrade the ASA version to stay on the latest maintenance release of your code. This way you stay ahead of any security issues or bugs that have been fixed in newer versions.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also a good idea to upgrade to stay ahead of any end of life code like version 8.2.</p>

<p>Upgrade major feature trains only when you need new features, or after train has matured.</p>

<h2>Enable unicast RPF</h2>

<p>Unicast RPF guards against IP spoofing (a packet uses an incorrect source IP address to obscure its true source) by ensuring that all packets have a source IP address that matches the correct source interface according to the routing table.</p>

<p>This is disabled by default. It&rsquo;s a good idea to enable it on every interface like this.</p>

<p><code>
ip verify reverse-path interface INSIDE
ip verify reverse-path interface OUTSIDE
ip verify reverse-path interface DMZ
ip verify reverse-path interface EXTRANET
</code></p>

<h2>Set embryonic limits</h2>

<p>An embryonic connection is also known as a half open connection. It means a SYN is a received, a SYN-ACK was sent back to the source, and we are waiting for the ACK back from the source. A lot of these indicates a DOS, or misconfiguration or another type of attack. Take a baseline of what is the normal amount of half open connections (<code>show conn</code> and look for aB, A, or SaAB connection flags) then double or triple that and make that your connection limit.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a good idea to set a limit for both incoming traffic to your servers, and outgoing traffic from your internal systems to the internet.</p>

<p>Sample code to permit only 100 embryonic connections to 192.168.1.50 on port 80. Also, this will only allow 25 connections per client to that host. Setting per-client-max is optional.</p>

<p><code>
access-list ACL-MAX-CONNS extended permit tcp any host 192.168.1.50 eq www
!
class-map CLASS-PROTECT
 description Protect web server from attacks
 match access-list ACL-MAX-CONNS
!
policy-map POL-MAX-CONNS
 class CLASS-PROTECT
  set connection embryonic-conn-max 100 per-client-max 25
!
service-policy POL-MAX-CONNS interface outside
</code></p>

<h2>Set maximum allowed connections</h2>

<p>If you have something like a NAT in your firewall that goes to an Apache web server to give that web server a public IP, set a limit to that web server so it matches what Apache can accept. If the configuration in the web server says there&rsquo;s only 25 connections allowed at once, set that on the ASA so the web server can&rsquo;t get DoS&rsquo;d.</p>

<p>Sample code for that may look like this below.</p>

<p><code>
access-list ACL-MAX-CONNS extended permit tcp any host 192.168.1.50 eq www
!
class-map CLASS-PROTECT
 description Protect web server from attacks
 match access-list ACL-MAX-CONNS
!
policy-map POL-MAX-CONNS
 class CLASS-PROTECT
  set connection conn-max 25
!
service-policy POL-MAX-CONNS interface outside
</code></p>

<h2>Enable logging</h2>

<p>By having logging enabled, it really assists on troubleshooting issues. It&rsquo;s one of the first things I will look at when troubleshooting.</p>

<p>By having logging enabled to send to a remote syslog server helps a lot more because now logs will be stored there a lot longer than what the ASA can hold. Also, if the ASA reboots the logs it had before the reboot are gone. If there&rsquo;s an issue occurring you can look back in history of the logs to see how many times it&rsquo;s happened in the past.</p>

<p>Also, all config changes will trigger a syslog message. Having that record is very helpful for finding problems.</p>

<p>Sample code to enable logging to be seen by both the &lsquo;show logg&rsquo; command and also to send all logs to 192.168.55.55 for remote storage.</p>

<p><code>
logging enable
logging timestamp
logging buffer-size 128000
logging buffered notifications
logging trap notifications
logging host INSIDE 192.168.55.55
</code></p>

<p>In the code above, only syslog level <code>notification</code> or above are being logged. But suppose you want get a certain log that&rsquo;s at <code>informational</code>. If you lower the log level to that, you&rsquo;ll get a lot more logs that may overwhelm your syslog server. Instead, find the syslog you want to raise the logging level and just adjust it to be at notification.</p>

<p><code>
logging message 302014 level notifications
</code></p>

<p>The config above will log traffic being permitted by the firewall.</p>

<p>Splunk is a sample tool that can monitor syslogs.</p>

<h2>Enable TACACS+ or RADIUS</h2>

<p>If you use shared logins and you see a config change that wasn&rsquo;t authorized, it may be really hard to find out who made the change. Also, what happens when someone with that login leaves the company.</p>

<p>A better alternative is to use AAA commands to enable a RADIUS or TACACS+ servers for authentication. This will ultimately result in better user control of who can access the firewall and have better visibility into what people are doing on the firewall.</p>

<p>Here is some sample code.</p>

<p>```
aaa-server TACACS+ protocol tacacs+
 reactivation-mode depletion deadtime 30
aaa-server TACACS+ (INSIDE) host 192.168.66.66
 timeout 3
 key s3kr3tk3y</p>

<p>aaa authentication http console TACACS+ LOCAL
aaa authentication ssh console TACACS+ LOCAL
aaa authentication enable console TACACS+ LOCAL
```</p>

<p>With the code above, all authentication will go to the TACACS+ server first. If that is unavailable then the local accounts are used for authentication as a fall back.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also a good idea to audit the local accounts regularly to make sure there aren&rsquo;t an unexpected accounts created. Also, rotate the passwords on these fallback accounts regularly too.</p>

<h2>Understand what is normal traffic</h2>

<p>Get to know what traffic is normal for your firewall. Do this so when there is an incident occurring or testing needs to be done, you have something to compare against.</p>

<p>Look at these areas to document what is normal traffic.</p>

<ul>
<li>Number of VPN connections and types of VPNs</li>
<li>Number of TCP/UDP connections</li>
<li>Number of active xlates</li>
<li>Interface usage</li>
<li>CPU and memory load</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conduct SNMP monitoring</h2>

<p>Have a server that you send SNMP traps to and have it also SNMP poll the ASA frequently. By monitoring this, you&rsquo;ll have a good understanding of when something is going wrong. Things that show up in SNMP logs are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Reboots</li>
<li>Failovers</li>
<li>High CPU</li>
<li>High Memory</li>
<li>Interface down</li>
<li>or any syslog can be converted to an SNMP trap</li>
</ul>


<p>Here is some sample code to enable SNMP:</p>

<p><code>
snmp-server host INSIDE 172.16.1.18 poll community s3kr3tkee version 2c
snmp-server host INSIDE 172.16.1.18 trap community s3kr3tkee version 2c
snmp-server community s3kr3tkee
snmp-server enable traps snmp authentication linkup linkdown coldstart warmstart
snmp-server enable traps entity config-change fru-insert fru-remove
snmp-server enable traps memory-threshold
snmp-server enable traps interface-threshold
snmp-server enable traps connection-limit-reached
snmp-server enable traps cpu threshold rising
snmp-server enable traps nat packet-discard
</code></p>

<p>MRTG is an example of a tool that can monitor this type of activity.</p>

<h2>Create a login banner</h2>

<p>There is a cyberlegend that talks about a case where a hacker gained access to a router and because the banner said &ldquo;Welcome to the system&rdquo; the judge dismissed the case. While this is not a true story, there is still a good lesson here. Create a banner that states unauthorized access is not allowed.</p>

<p>Example banner:</p>

<p><code>
banner motd *******************************************************************
banner motd THIS SYSTEM ACCESSES PROPRIETARY INFORMATION.  ACCESS IS RESTRICTED
banner motd TO AUTHORIZED USERS ONLY FOR LEGITIMATE BUSINESS PURPOSES.
banner motd UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS IS A VIOLATION OF STATE AND FEDERAL, CIVIL AND
banner motd CRIMINAL LAWS. ALL ACTIONS ARE BEING RECORDED.
banner motd PLEASE LOG OFF.
banner motd *******************************************************************
</code></p>

<h2>Turn telnet off</h2>

<p>Telnet is an insecure protocol. When you login to a device using telnet, your password goes over the wire in clear text for anyone to listen in on it. Use ssh instead. Never use telnet.</p>

<p>Conduct <code>show run telnet</code> and verify there are no subnets listed.</p>

<h2>Verify ssh and http subnets</h2>

<p>In the ASA do a <code>show run ssh</code> and <code>show run http</code>. Look at the subnets that are listed. Verify those are what you wish to allow.</p>

<p>You would never want to see this on a firewall:</p>

<p><code>
ssh 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 OUTSIDE
</code></p>

<p>It essentially means anyone on any IP on the outside can ssh to this firewall. Lock down the firewall to only permit subnets that firewall admins are on.</p>

<h2>Permit as little as possible</h2>

<p>One of the fundamental differences between a router and a firewall is that one wants to permit as much as possible and the other wants to deny as much as possible.</p>

<p>If you only have 5 valid subnets on the inside of your network, only permit those 5 subnets to pass through the firewall to the internet. This saves you from incidents where spoofed IPs inside the network cannot leave.</p>

<p>Restrict inbound connections to only the IPs that need inbound connections and only on the ports that are open. An example of this is a web server. Permit only inbound 80 and 443 for http and https. You don&rsquo;t want to permit ssh or telnet to that host or it will constantly be hit from the internet. Only permit what is needed and stop there.</p>

<h2>Remove unused configs</h2>

<p>Review the firewall config each quarter and remove any configs that are no longer valid on your network. For instance if you decommissioned a subnet in your network, remove that subnet from the firewall. You only want to permit the traffic through your firewall that you know is valid.</p>

<p>Try the <a href="/config-cleanup/">Cisco ASA config cleanup tool</a> here on TunnelsUp.</p>

<p>Each quarter, review the following configs to verify they are still valid</p>

<ul>
<li>ACLs</li>
<li>NATs</li>
<li>VPNs</li>
<li>Objects/Object-groups</li>
</ul>


<h2>Add an explicit deny any to all interface ACLs</h2>

<p>At the end of an ACL is an implicit deny any any. So why explicitly add it?</p>

<ul>
<li>Lets you know how many hits are hitting it</li>
<li>Avoids any vulnerabilities that might let someone bypass it</li>
<li>Makes the ACL easier to read</li>
</ul>


<h2>Reference</h2>

<p>Here is a PDF of more best practices suggested by the NSA.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.iad.gov/iad/customcf/openAttachment.cfm?FilePath=/iad/library/ia-guidance/security-configuration/networks/assets/public/upload/Cisco-ASA-Out-of-the-Box-Security-Configuration-Guide.pdf">https://www.iad.gov/iad/customcf/openAttachment.cfm?FilePath=/iad/library/ia-guidance/security-configuration/networks/assets/public/upload/Cisco-ASA-Out-of-the-Box-Security-Configuration-Guide.pdf</a></p>

<br><br>


<p>Cisco Validated Design</p>

<p><a href="https://cisco.com/go/cvd">https://cisco.com/go/cvd</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
