<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: asa | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tup/tag/asa/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/"/>
  <updated>2022-09-10T14:59:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cisco ASA Drop Reason: Unexpected-Packet]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-drop-reason-unexpected-packet/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-23T21:05:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-drop-reason-unexpected-packet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was trying to send management traffic over a VPN tunnel to a Cisco ASA that terminated the tunnel. I ran into some problems doing this and I want to document my troubleshooting steps.</p>

<h3>Config</h3>

<p>Before attempting to ssh to the ASA I made sure that ssh to the ASA worked when coming from the inside of the network.</p>

<p>Then I applied the config:</p>

<p><code>
ssh 10.0.0.0 255.0.0.0 INSIDE
management-access INSIDE
</code></p>

<p>Even though we are coming from the OUTSIDE, when it comes over the VPN tunnel we can get into the ASA through the INSIDE interface. Going over the VPN tunnel for ssh is more secure than doing it directly over the Internet. This also means you&rsquo;ll be sshing to the IP that is on the INSIDE of your ASA.</p>

<h3>Errors</h3>

<p>Well this didn&rsquo;t work and to see the drop reason we can do a asp-drop capture like this:</p>

<p><code>cap cap1 type asp-drop all</code></p>

<p>Then I looked at the cap including just the IP I was after and saw this:</p>

<p><code>
ASA5508# sh cap cap1 | i 192.168.128.5
   9: 17:40:03.527957       10.50.101.6 &gt; 192.168.128.5: icmp: echo request Drop-reason: (unexpected-packet) Unexpected packet
  10: 17:40:03.641858       10.2.11.50.49955 &gt; 192.168.128.5.161:  udp 75 Drop-reason: (unexpected-packet) Unexpected packet
  17: 17:40:05.520206       10.50.101.6 &gt; 192.168.128.5: icmp: echo request
  24: 17:40:07.320402       10.2.11.50 &gt; 192.168.128.5: icmp: echo request Drop-reason: (unexpected-packet) Unexpected packet
  58: 17:40:22.546907       10.50.101.6.1030 &gt; 192.168.128.5.22: S 1027314954:1027314954(0) win 4128 &lt;mss 536&gt; Drop-reason: (unexpected-packet) Unexpected packet
  64: 17:40:24.540224       10.50.101.6.1030 &gt; 192.168.128.5.22: S 1027314954:1027314954(0) win 4128 &lt;mss 536&gt; Drop-reason: (unexpected-packet) Unexpected packet
  67: 17:40:25.106302       10.2.11.50.39489 &gt; 192.168.128.5.161:  udp 41 Drop-reason: (unexpected-packet) Unexpected packet
  77: 17:40:28.541292       10.50.101.6.1030 &gt; 192.168.128.5.22: S 1027314954:1027314954(0) win 4128 &lt;mss 536&gt; Drop-reason: (unexpected-packet) Unexpected packet
  84: 17:40:30.111276       10.2.11.50.39489 &gt; 192.168.128.5.161:  udp 41 Drop-reason: (unexpected-packet) Unexpected packet
</code></p>

<p>Now we have narrowed down this issue to be a drop reason of &ldquo;unexpected-packet&rdquo;.</p>

<h3>Fix</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/asa/asa-command-reference/show_asp_drop/show_asp_drop.html">Cisco Writes:</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Unexpected-Packet occurs when the appliance in transparent mode receives a non-IP packet, destined to its MAC address, but there is no corresponding service running on the appliance to process the packet.</p></blockquote>

<p>But in my case this is neither a non-IP packet, nor is this firewall in transparent mode. So because Cisco is flat out wrong here, a blog post was obligatory.</p>

<p>We actually need to take a look at our <strong>NAT</strong> commands. Specifically adding the <code>route-lookup</code> option to our NAT.</p>

<p>My <strong>NONAT</strong> statement looked like this:</p>

<p><code>nat (INSIDE,any) source static LOCAL-NETS LOCAL-NETS destination static REMOTE-NETS REMOTE-NETS</code></p>

<p>This was changed to become:</p>

<p><code>nat (INSIDE,any) source static LOCAL-NETS LOCAL-NETS destination static REMOTE-NETS REMOTE-NETS route-lookup</code></p>

<p>After that, the ssh worked.</p>

<h3>Reason</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/asa/asa-command-reference/I-R/cmdref2/n.html">Cisco Writes the route-lookup command:</a></p>

<blockquote><p>For identity NAT in routed mode, determines the egress interface using a route lookup instead of using the interface specified in the NAT command. If you do not specify interfaces in the NAT command, a route lookup is used by default.</p></blockquote>

<p>That means, if you have <code>any</code> in your NAT statement, the ASA isn&rsquo;t sure what interface to route the packet to (yes, even though the ASA HAS this IP on it&rsquo;s interface). By adding <code>route-lookup</code> the ASA decides to check the routing table to determine what interface to send the packet to.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Upgrade a Cisco ASA Firewall]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/how-to-upgrade-a-cisco-asa-firewall/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-17T22:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/how-to-upgrade-a-cisco-asa-firewall</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To upgrade the OS of a Cisco ASA firewall follow these basic steps:</p>

<ol>
<li>Download Software</li>
<li>Get Software on ASA</li>
<li>Verify Software</li>
<li>Configure ASA</li>
<li>Reboot ASA</li>
</ol>


<h3>Download Software</h3>

<p>The general suggestion is to run the latest version of ASA OS version that the ASA supports. The OS image contains the entire OS. There are no such things as patches or updates. You download a whole new OS to be installed. Because of this there usually isn&rsquo;t a need to do a stepped upgrade. The only time you need to do a <a href="/cisco-asa-upgrade-path/">stepped upgrade is when you&rsquo;re upgrading from a very old version (pre 9.1)</a> and want the config to be migrated for you.</p>

<p>Go to the downloads section of Cisco.com (requires Cisco login with valid support contract): <a href="https://software.cisco.com/download">https://software.cisco.com/download/</a></p>

<p><strong>ASA Without FirePower IPS</strong></p>

<p>Navigate to <strong>Security</strong> > <strong>Firewalls</strong> > <strong>Adaptive Security Appliace (ASA)</strong> > <strong>ASA Model</strong> > <strong>Software on Chassis</strong> > <strong>Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>ASA With FirePower IPS</strong></p>

<p>Navigate to <strong>Security</strong> > <strong>Firewalls</strong> > <strong>Next-Generation Firewalls (NGFW)</strong> > <strong>ASA 5500-X with FirePOWER Services</strong> > <strong>Model of ASA</strong> > <strong>Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>When downloading the software, hover over the image on the downloads page to see the Checksum. Copy this checksum as we&rsquo;ll use it to verify the image later.</p></blockquote>

<h4>Understanding Versions</h4>

<p>Unlike a Cisco Router image, the ASA image contains all features and requires additional licenses to unlock the features. This makes choosing the image a lot easier but makes handling licensing harder.</p>

<p>The OS image file will look like one of these 3:</p>

<p><code>asa933-7-lfbff-k8.SPA</code><br>
<code>asa924-5-smp-K8.bin</code><br>
<code>asa924-5-k8.bin</code></p>

<p>The numbers indicate the version. For instance the first file here is for ASA OS Version 9.3(3)7.</p>

<p>The <code>lfbff</code> and <code>SPA</code> indicates it has FirePower IPS included in the image and this image is digitally signed which makes it tamper resistant.</p>

<p>The <code>smp</code> indicates the image is for a multi-core ASA (check how many cores using show ver).</p>

<p>The 3rd one is for old ASAs that have a single core.</p>

<p>The <code>k8</code> tag indicates this image supports DES encryption. With a license, you can make the ASA support AES and 3DES.</p>

<p>These images aren&rsquo;t tied to a model number, so the image downloaded for a 5512x can also be used on a 5516x.</p>

<h2>Get Software on ASA</h2>

<p>Once you have downloaded the image, upload it to the ASA.</p>

<p>Upload the image to an http or ftp server and copy the image to the ASA from the ASA command line with one of these commands:</p>

<p><code>copy http flash</code></p>

<p><code>copy ftp flash</code></p>

<p><code>copy tftp flash</code></p>

<p>You can also use a USB flash drive to put the image on and insert it into the ASA.</p>

<p><code>dir /all</code> will show you all the files on all disks</p>

<p><code>copy disk1:/filename flash</code></p>

<p>It is also possible to upload the image using the ASDM.</p>

<h2>Verify Software</h2>

<p>Now that the software is on the ASA you want to verify it got there without any errors. To do this, use the <code>verify</code> CLI command:</p>

<p><code>verify disk0:/asaxxxxxxxx.xxx</code></p>

<p>Now compare the checksum output to the checksum you saw on the downloads page from Cisco.com. If they match then this image is not corrupt.</p>

<h2>Configure ASA</h2>

<p>Apply the image to the ASA with the <code>boot system</code> command like this:</p>

<p><code>boot system disk0:/asa962-13-lfbff-k8.SPA</code></p>

<p>This will tell the ASA to boot to that image the next time there is a reboot.</p>

<h2>Reboot ASA</h2>

<p>Lastly, reboot the ASA. When it comes back up, check the version doing a <code>show ver</code>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ASA5506x Fits In A 5505 Rack Mount]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/asa5505x-fits-in-a-5505-rack-mount/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-01T22:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/asa5505x-fits-in-a-5505-rack-mount</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The rack mount kits for a Cisco ASA 5506x (Part number ASA-5506-RACK-MNT=) are going for over $250! That&rsquo;s almost as much as the firewall itself! This is ridiculously high.</p>

<p>But don&rsquo;t panic! You can get an older ASA 5505 rack mount kit and the 5506x will fit inside it. The older ASA 5505 mounts go for $60 or less and seem to be ok. Here are some pics from a recent swap I did.</p>

<p>ASA 5505 in an 5505 rack mount.
<img src="/images/asarack1.jpg"></p>

<p>ASA 5506x in a 5505 rack mount.
<img src="/images/asarack2.jpg"></p>

<p>ASA 5506x in a 5505 rack mount.
<img src="/images/asarack3.jpg"></p>

<p>The one problem here is that the 5506-X is longer than the 5505. This means you may have to secure it using some zip ties or something if you don&rsquo;t want it to slide around every time you put a cable in. In my case I added a few pieces of tape to keep it from moving and it worked great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cisco ASA command to show listening ports]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-command-to-show-listening-ports/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-29T15:05:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/cisco-asa-command-to-show-listening-ports</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you wish there was a <code>netstat</code> command for a Cisco ASA? Are you looking to see what ports the ASA has open and is listening on? Try this command:</p>

<p>```
ASA5506# sh asp table socket</p>

<p>Protocol  Socket    State      Local Address        Foreign Address
SSL       0001ebf8  LISTEN     172.16.3.1:443       0.0.0.0:<em>
TCP       000216f8  LISTEN     172.16.3.1:22        0.0.0.0:</em>
TCP       370c1d68  LISTEN     99.99.99.99:22       0.0.0.0:*
TCP       3712d678  ESTAB      172.16.3.1:22        172.16.2.3:50233
```</p>

<p>This command displays all of the ports that are open and established on the ASA.</p>

<p>The <code>state</code> indicates whether the port is listening or established.</p>

<p>The <code>local address</code> says which IP it&rsquo;s listening on. In the example above, 99.99.99.99 is the outside interface and the 172.16.3.1 is the inside interface.</p>

<p>The <code>foreign address</code> will show up when someone connects to that port. In this case I was ssh&rsquo;d into the firewall coming from 172.16.2.3.</p>

<p>The output above should be a direct reflection of the <code>ssh</code>, <code>telnet</code>, and <code>http</code> commands in the ASA.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to show and clear user sessions on a Cisco ASA]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/how-to-show-and-clear-user-sessions-on-a-cisco-asa/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-18T16:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/how-to-show-and-clear-user-sessions-on-a-cisco-asa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you need to disconnect someone&rsquo;s ssh session to a Cisco ASA. This may be needed because users haven&rsquo;t logged out properly and have taken up all the sessions allowed.</p>

<h2>Check Usage Limits</h2>

<p>You can check usage limits by seeing how many sessions the ASA <em>thinks</em> are connected.</p>

<p><code>
FWL1# show resource usage resource ssh
Resource                 Current        Peak      Limit        Denied Context
SSH Server                     5           5          5           109 System
</code></p>

<p>In this case the ASA can only connect 5 years and it thinks there are 5 sessions open and therefore it cannot connect any more.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a bug that doesn&rsquo;t properly release sessions from the ASA. <a href="https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCsm68097">https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCsm68097</a></p>

<h2>Show current ssh sessions</h2>

<p>To display all ssh sessions connected run this command.</p>

<p>```
FWL1# show ssh sessions                      <br/>
SID Client IP       Version Mode Encryption Hmac     State            Username
0   10.1.1.21       2.0     IN   aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   james</p>

<pre><code>                        OUT  aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   james
</code></pre>

<p>2   10.1.1.22       2.0     IN   aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   frank</p>

<pre><code>                        OUT  aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   frank
</code></pre>

<p>3   10.1.1.20       2.0     IN   aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   henry</p>

<pre><code>                        OUT  aes128-ctr sha1     SessionStarted   henry
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<h2>Disconnect user</h2>

<p>If you want to disconnect user henry, find the SID and use this command:</p>

<p><code>
FWL1# ssh disconnect 3
</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
