<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ux | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="http://tunnelsup.github.io/tup/tag/ux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tunnelsup.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-29T22:41:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tunnelsup.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Customer Service on the web]]></title>
    <link href="http://tunnelsup.github.io/customer-service-on-the-web/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-20T21:31:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://tunnelsup.github.io/customer-service-on-the-web</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is it possible for a website to have good customer service? How can that be defined? I recently attended a lecture that attempted to define what good customer service is. It wasn&rsquo;t intended for the web but more of a face to face experience like in a restaurant. Upon listening to the lecture I started connecting it to how it relates to the web.</p>

<p>The lecture explained that there are 5 dimensions to customer service. I will go over each of them and what that means for for a face to face interaction like in a restaurant and what I think it means on a webpage.</p>

<p>Imagine if you go to a restaurant, how many of these 5 things can be bad before you have a bad experience? Just one. I think the same is true for the online experience. Just one of these things can be bad and the whole user experience becomes bad.</p>

<h2>Reliability</h2>

<p>The ability to provide what was promised dependably and accurately.</p>

<h4>In A Restaurant</h4>

<ul>
<li>If you order a salad without cheese that better be what you received.</li>
<li>If the menu says there are vegan options, the server better know what the word vegan means.</li>
<li>If the hours are specified on the door the place better be open during those times or having a sign explaining a special circumstance.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Online</h4>

<ul>
<li>The website should be up and available 24/7/365.</li>
<li>The website should respond to any combination of www, non-www, http, https. It can redirect the user to the correct one but should respond to all of them.</li>
<li>Things that look like links or buttons on the webpage should actually be links and buttons that work and do something.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Assurance</h2>

<p>The knowledge and courtesy of employees, and their ability to convey trust and confidence.</p>

<h4>In A Restaurant</h4>

<ul>
<li>If you ask about what ingredients are in a meal the server shouldn&rsquo;t just shrug and say they don&rsquo;t know.</li>
<li>The staff should be courteous and kind to the customers.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Online</h4>

<ul>
<li>The site better be secure and any information I give should not be given to people I don&rsquo;t want to give it to.</li>
<li>Are there typos on the site?</li>
<li>Does the copy (words on the page) look great? Things should be explained simply and quickly but accurately.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Empathy</h2>

<p>The degree of caring and individual attention provided to customers.</p>

<h4>In A Restaurant</h4>

<ul>
<li>The server should check on you frequently to make sure there isn&rsquo;t anything you need.</li>
<li>The chef should care about the quality of ingredients and how the meal tastes.</li>
<li>The chef should take time to make the presentation of the dish great. I don&rsquo;t want to eat out of a horse trough. I like my food to be presented in a way that looks delicious.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Online</h4>

<ul>
<li>Is the website user friendly and give the user a simple path to the goal they have?</li>
<li>Can I figure out what the website does quickly and know what it can do to help me?</li>
<li>Does the website have a simple and intuitive user interface or require extensive help or a manual to figure out how to use it?</li>
</ul>


<p>In my opinion, a website that has poor usability is equivalent to having a server that was rude to you in a restaurant. The website didn&rsquo;t try to put your needs first which is ease of use and getting your tasks done quickly.</p>

<h2>Responsiveness</h2>

<p>The willingness to help customers and provide prompt service.</p>

<h4>In A Restaurant</h4>

<ul>
<li>If you ask for a refill on your drink it should arrive quickly and not 30 minutes later or worse, never.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Online</h4>

<ul>
<li>Does the site allow a user to navigate it easily?</li>
<li>If I get lost on the site is it easy to go back to a familiar page?</li>
<li>Does the website offer help on hard to understand sections?</li>
<li>Is there confusing terminology that only an expert would understand?</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tangibles</h2>

<p>The physical facilities and equipment, and the appearance of personnel.</p>

<h4>In A Restaurant</h4>

<ul>
<li>Was the bathroom clean?</li>
<li>Was your fork clean?</li>
<li>Did the staff appear to have good hygiene?</li>
</ul>


<h4>Online</h4>

<ul>
<li>Does the color scheme look good?</li>
<li>Are the fonts readable?</li>
<li>Does the overall style and appearance of the site look good?</li>
<li>Do the pictures match the content or help me in any way?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
