<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: spam | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tup/tag/spam/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-06-29T13:35:45-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Differences between spam and phishing emails]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/differences-between-spam-and-phishing-emails/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-15T14:47:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/differences-between-spam-and-phishing-emails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes people send me spam mail and tell me they are being phished. Sometimes people ignore phishing emails thinking they are spam. Let&rsquo;s try to understand the differences of the two.</p>

<h2>Definitions</h2>

<p>Spam is:</p>

<blockquote><p>Unsolicited e-mail, often of a commercial nature, sent indiscriminately to multiple mailing lists, individuals, or newsgroups; junk e-mail.</p></blockquote>

<p>Phishing is:</p>

<blockquote><p>To request confidential information over the Internet under false pretenses in order to fraudulently obtain credit card numbers, passwords, or other personal data.</p></blockquote>

<h2>Spam Vs Phishing</h2>

<p>Here are some key differences.</p>

<ul>
<li>Phishing emails are usually targeted to a person. They will often have the person&rsquo;s name already in the email. Spam is more likely to be less personal.</li>
<li>Phishing usually has a sense of urgency. There may be language like &ldquo;free to first 50 people&rdquo;. Spam may not be so immediate.</li>
<li>Phishing usually is trying to get you to click a malicious link or reply to an email (instead of making a phone call).</li>
<li>Phishing links often contain malware or are intended to trick you. Spam links are often to legitimate services and websites that want to sell you a product.</li>
<li>Phishing emails are sent much less frequent than spam.</li>
<li>Phishing emails often are impersonating another company or someone you know. For instance an email that looks like it&rsquo;s from your bank but really not. Spam emails usually don&rsquo;t impersonate or try to trick you into thinking they are someone else.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Samples</h2>

<h4>Sample Spam Email</h4>

<p><img src="/images/spamphish2.png"></p>

<p>First of all this email isn&rsquo;t even to me, it&rsquo;s to someone else and I&rsquo;m in the bcc field. This email looks like it can be sent to thousands of people and not just me. Lastly, the link does in fact take you to a dating site so it&rsquo;s really just an advertisement.</p>

<h4>Sample Phishing Email</h4>

<p><img src="/images/spamphish1.png"></p>

<p>This email looks like it came from Google and I have a new message. This makes it feel like it&rsquo;s directed only to me. But looking at the from address, you can see it&rsquo;s not from Google. Hovering over the links all show that it doesn&rsquo;t take you to a Google website either.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
