<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: color | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tup/tag/color/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/"/>
  <updated>2022-07-18T21:59:56-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sublime Text 2 - Cisco Syntax and Snippets]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/sublime-text-2-cisco-syntax-and-snippets/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/sublime-text-2-cisco-syntax-and-snippets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a bit of a geek when it comes to workflow and that means I have tried out many text editors. Notepad, Notepad++, TextMate, Crimson Editor and VIM were all favorites of mine at one point. Now there is one that truly stands out as being superior for me. That is Sublime Text 2. I won&rsquo;t go into how awesome this text editor is in this post, I will leave that for you to find out on your own. This text editor is geared towards programmers though. No matter how much I searched I could not find anyone who has integrated it with Cisco. Here are some links to my github account which includes Cisco Syntax Definitions and Cisco Snippets for Sublime Text 2.</p>

<h2>Cisco Syntax Definitions for Sublime Text 2/3</h2>

<p>What does this mean? Take a look at this screenshot from a recent script I was working on in Sublime Text 2:</p>

<p><img src="/images/Sublime-Cisco-Syntax.png" alt="Syntax example - IMG" /></p>

<p>The Cisco Syntax definitions looks for specific keywords in a .txt or .cfg file and highlights them. In the example above I am using the Eifel color scheme which goes well with it.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/tunnelsup/sublime-cisco-syntax">Click here for the github repository for Cisco Syntax Definitions for Sublime Text 2.</a></p>

<h2>Cisco Snippets for Sublime Text 2</h2>

<p>Snippets are a super cool productivity enhancer for me when working with Cisco devices. With snippets I can type a short word like &lsquo;static&rsquo; and it expands into a multi line script which is essentially a framework for a static NAT config. Take a look at this example.</p>

<p><img src="/images/static_1.gif" alt="Cisco Snippets - IMG" /></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/tunnelsup/sublime-cisco-snippets">Click here for the github repository of my Cisco Snippets for Sublime Text 2.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
