<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: break sequence | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tup/tag/break-sequence/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-01-15T19:52:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recovering the password when No Service Password-Recovery is enabled on a router]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/recovering-the-password-when-no-service-password-recovery-is-enabled-on-a-router/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/recovering-the-password-when-no-service-password-recovery-is-enabled-on-a-router</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Goal: Get into an 1811 that has the No Service Password-Recovery feature enabled.</p>

<p>Limitation: Because this feature is enabled it simply means when you do password recovery the entire config will be wiped.</p>

<p>Problem: <a href="http://www.cisco.com/en/US/docs/ios/12_3/12_3y/12_3ya8/gtnsvpwd.html#wp1062060">Cisco&rsquo;s documentation on this is WRONG. </a></p>

<p>Solution: Using SecureCRT and consoled into the router the break sequence is CTRL+BREAK (if you are on a lenovo laptop then hold CTRL then push Fn+BREAK). You have to send it at the right time. Look at the output below to see when to hit the break sequence.</p>

<pre><code>
System Bootstrap, Version 12.3(8r)YH13, RELEASE SOFTWARE (fc1)
Technical Support: http://www.cisco.com/techsupport
Copyright (c) 2008 by cisco Systems, Inc.
C1800 platform with 131072 Kbytes of main memory with parity disabled

Readonly ROMMON initialized
PASSWORD RECOVERY FUNCTIONALITY IS DISABLED
program load complete, entry point: 0x80012000, size: 0xc0c0

Initializing ATA monitor library.......
program load complete, entry point: 0x80012000, size: 0xc0c0

Initializing ATA monitor library.......

program load complete, entry point: 0x80012000, size: 0x1974ba0
Self decompressing the image : ######################################################################
######################################################################
######################################################################
################################ [OK]

Restricted Rights Legend

Use, duplication, or disclosure by the Government is
subject to restrictions as set forth in subparagraph
(c) of the Commercial Computer Software - Restricted
Rights clause at FAR sec. 52.227-19 and subparagraph
(c) (1) (ii) of the Rights in Technical Data and Computer
Software clause at DFARS sec. 252.227-7013.

cisco Systems, Inc.
170 West Tasman Drive
San Jose, California 95134-1706

Cisco IOS Software, C181X Software (C181X-ADVIPSERVICESK9-M), Version 15.0(1)M3, RELEASE SOFTWARE (fc2)
Technical Support: http://www.cisco.com/techsupport
Copyright (c) 1986-2010 by Cisco Systems, Inc.
Compiled Sun 18-Jul-10 00:57 by prod_rel_team
Image text-base: 0x80012118, data-base: 0x82E13000
<strong><span style="color: #ff0000;">[ 5 Second window begins here to send BREAK ]</span></strong>

PASSWORD RECOVERY IS DISABLED.
Do you want to reset the router to factory default
configuration and proceed [y/n] ? <strong>y</strong>
Reset router configuration to factory default.

This product contains cryptographic features and is subject to United
States and local country laws governing import, export, transfer and
use. Delivery of Cisco cryptographic products does not imply
third-party authority to import, export, distribute or use encryption.
Importers, exporters, distributors and users are responsible for
compliance with U.S. and local country laws. By using this product you
agree to comply with applicable laws and regulations. If you are unable
to comply with U.S. and local laws, return this product immediately.

A summary of U.S. laws governing Cisco cryptographic products may be found at:
http://www.cisco.com/wwl/export/crypto/tool/stqrg.html

If you require further assistance please contact us by sending email to
export@cisco.com.

Installed image archive
Cisco 1811 (MPC8500) processor (revision 0x400) with 118784K/12288K bytes of memory.
Processor board ID FTX141780Z7, with hardware revision 0000

10 FastEthernet interfaces
1 Serial interface
1 terminal line
1 Virtual Private Network (VPN) Module
62720K bytes of ATA CompactFlash (Read/Write)
[OK][OK]
SETUP: new interface FastEthernet0 placed in "shutdown" state
SETUP: new interface FastEthernet1 placed in "shutdown" state

Press RET5 01:35:07.427: %LINK-5-CHANGED: Interface FastEthernet0, changed state to administratively down
*Jan  5 01:35:07.431: %SYS-5-RESTART: System restarted --
Cisco IOS Software, C181X Software (C181X-ADVIPSERVICESK9-M), Version 15.0(1)M3, RELEASE SOFTWARE (fc2)
Technical Support: http://www.cisco.com/techsupport
Copyright (c) 1986-2010 by Cisco Systems, Inc.
Compiled Sun 18-Jul-10 00:57 by prod_rel_team
*Jan  5 01:35:07.431: %SNMP-5-COLDSTART: SNMP agent on host Router is undergoing a cold start
*Jan  5 01:35:07.459: %CRYPTO-6-ISAKMP_ON_OFF: ISAKMP is OFF
*Jan  5 01:35:07.459: %CRYPTO-6-GDOI_ON_OFF: GDOI is OFF
*Jan  5 01:35:07.943: %LINK-5-CHANGED: Interface FastEthernet1, changed state to administratively down
*Jan  5 01:35:08.823: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface FastEthernet2, changed state to up
*Jan  5 01:35:08.823: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface FastEthernet3, changed state to up
*Jan  5 01:35:08.823: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface FastEthernet4, changed state to up
*Jan  5 01:35:08.827: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface FastEthernet5, changed state to up
*Jan  5 01:35:08.827: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface FastEthernet6, changed state to up
*Jan  5 01:35:08.827: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface FastEthernet7, changed state to up
*Jan  5 01:35:08.831: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface FastEthernet8, changed state to up
*Jan  5 01:35:08.831: %LINK-3-UPDOWN: Interface FastEthernet9, changed state to up
*Jan  5 01:35:09.823: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface FastEthernet2, changed state to down
*Jan  5 01:35:09.823: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface FastEthernet3, changed state to down
*Jan  5 01:35:09.823: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface FastEthernet4, changed state to down
*Jan  5 01:35:09.827: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface FastEthernet5, changed state to down
*Jan  5 01:35:09.827: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface FastEthernet6, changed state to down
*Jan  5 01:35:09.827: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface FastEthernet7, changed state to down
*Jan  5 01:35:09.831: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface FastEthernet8, changed state to down
*Jan  5 01:35:09.831: %LINEPROTO-5-UPDOWN: Line protocol on Interface FastEthernet9, changed state to down
Router&gt;
</code></pre>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
