<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: misc | TunnelsUP]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/tup/tag/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-05-25T12:26:29-07:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything You Need to Know About Websites Port Scanning You]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/browser-portscanning/"/>
    <updated>2020-05-25T10:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/browser-portscanning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some websites can and do port scan you when you visit their site. This is sneaky and creepy behavior and I want to tell you about it.</p>

<h2>What it looks like</h2>

<p>First of all this is not your run of the mill port scanning. This isn&rsquo;t someone firing off a bunch of packets at you on different ports looking to see what you have open. No this is all done in the browser through javascript, where a website is instructing <em>your computer</em> to port scan itself, then report the results to the website.</p>

<p>Today I loaded up Microsoft Edge browser (version 44), enabled developer tools, looked at the network traffic and visited eBay.com. This is what I saw.</p>

<p><img src="/images/portscan1.jpg" alt="eBay Port Scan" /></p>

<p>As you can see the website has triggered a series of GET requests to 127.0.0.1 on 14 different ports. 127.0.0.1 is the loopback address of every computer in the world. If try to connect to that IP you will always be connecting the computer you are on. So when you visit the website, it instructs your computer, to check if these 14 ports are open, on your own computer.</p>

<p>These ports are:</p>

<table class="table"><tbody><tr><th>Program</th>
<th>Name</th>
<th>Port</th>
</tr><tr><td><strong>Unknown</strong></td>
<td>REF</td>
<td>63333</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>VNC</strong></td>
<td>VNC</td>
<td>5900</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>VNC</strong></td>
<td>VNC</td>
<td>5901</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>VNC</strong></td>
<td>VNC</td>
<td>5902</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>VNC</strong></td>
<td>VNC</td>
<td>5903</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>Remote Desktop Protocol</strong></td>
<td>RDP</td>
<td>3389</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>Aeroadmin</strong></td>
<td>ARO</td>
<td>5950</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>Ammyy Admin</strong></td>
<td>AMY</td>
<td>5931</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>TeamViewer</strong></td>
<td>TV0</td>
<td>5939</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>TeamViewer</strong></td>
<td>TV1</td>
<td>6039</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>TeamViewer</strong></td>
<td>TV2</td>
<td>5944</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>TeamViewer</strong></td>
<td>TV2</td>
<td>6040</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>Anyplace Control</strong></td>
<td>APC</td>
<td>5279</td>
</tr><tr><td><strong>AnyDesk</strong></td>
<td>ANY</td>
<td>7070</td>
</tr></tbody></table>


<p>By the way, thank you to Charlie Belmer for his blog post <a href="https://nullsweep.com/why-is-this-website-port-scanning-me/">Why Is This Website Port Scanning Me</a> which introduced me to this problem, and I only caught that post through this <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23246170">Hacker News</a> posting.</p>

<p>Also if you want to test this on your own, be aware that eBay only does this on the first visit to the website.</p>

<h2>How to Block This</h2>

<p>Ok first, strait up, this is creepy and I think it&rsquo;s invasive. I do not want to allow websites to do this to my computer. It&rsquo;s bypassing all the network security I have put in place. It bypasses my firewall, my AV, and my Pi Hole. Because the website instructed my computer to conduct these scans, and it&rsquo;s not coming from the internet.</p>

<p>So how do you stop it?</p>

<p>There are two browser extension that seem to do pretty good at stopping this:</p>

<p><a href="https://privacybadger.org/">Privacy Badger</a> and <a href="https://getublock.com/">uBlock Origin</a>.</p>

<p>But some browser block this behavior by default too. Brave and Opera seem to block this by default.</p>

<p>Users have reported to me that they see this scanning behavior is permitted in Chrome, Firefox, and Edge when they have no extensions enabled.</p>

<p>Also it&rsquo;s worth noting that the <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/10419">tor browser blocks this</a> specifically.</p>

<h2>eBay is not the only ones doing this</h2>

<p>After <a href="https://twitter.com/JackRhysider/status/1264415919691841536">raising these concerns on Twitter</a> I started getting information from people far and wide. I quickly learned that eBay is using a solution called <a href="https://risk.lexisnexis.com/products/threatmetrix">Threat Metrix</a> to conduct this. And <a href="https://www.featuredcustomers.com/vendor/threatmetrix/customers">here&rsquo;s a client list</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/portscan2.jpg" alt="Port Scan Info" /></p>

<p>Some big names on this list. GoPro, WePay, Netflix, Visa, Yandex, TripAdvisor, and a bunch of dating sites and finance sites. I visited 5 of these sites and watched the network traffic and didn&rsquo;t see the same scanning behavior. But perhaps it only happens when you login or when you go to purchase something. So potentially all of these have the technology to do this to their customers.</p>

<p>But wait. That&rsquo;s just one vendor. One solution. Surely they have competitors right? Here&rsquo;s a report from <a href="https://solutionsreview.com/identity-management/key-findings-gartner-market-guide-identity-proofing-corroboration/">Gartner regarding Identity Proofing</a>.</p>

<p>In this there are a list of Recommended Vendors.</p>

<blockquote><p>Gartner named Acuant, BioCatch, Buguroo, Emailage, Experian, EZMCOM, Fraud.net, IBM Trusteer, ID Analytics, IdentityMind, IDology, iovation, Jumio, Kount, LexisNexis Risk Solutions, Mitek, Nuance, NuData Security (A Mastercard Company), Pindrop, SecuredTorch, ThreatMetrix (A LexisNexis Risk Solutions COmpany), TransUnion, TRUSTID, and Whitepages Pro as Representative Vendors in the market.</p></blockquote>

<p>ThreatMetrix is in there. But there are so many more, even IBM has a solution to do this.</p>

<p>But whoa. This suddenly became a huge market. This means that there are likely a lot of websites doing this.</p>

<p>But wait, this isn&rsquo;t new either. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AskNetsec/comments/4j0nas/why_is_facebook_checking_my_open_ports/">Facebook was scanning their visitors back in 2016</a>.</p>

<h2>So why are they port scanning us?</h2>

<p>I think the easiest way to explain this is to look at ThreatMetrix&rsquo;s feature list. Here&rsquo;s a snippet from <a href="https://risk.lexisnexis.com/products/threatmetrix">their website</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Context-based information</strong> detects bot attacks to perform behavioral analysis of users during periods of normal operation and compares such data to that gathered during an attack, enabling the ability to differentiate between a human and a bot the moment they login/transact.</li>
<li><strong>Deep connection analysis</strong> technologies detect the use of technologies such as hidden proxies and VPNs and allow the bank to see the true IP address, geolocation and other attributes of each event, backed by global identity data over time.</li>
<li><strong>Malware protection</strong> helps businesses mitigate the risk by being protected from Man-In-The-Browser (MITB), Remote Access Trojan (RAT), high velocity/frequency bot attacks to low-and- slow attacks mimicking legitimate customer behavior, ransomware, key logging attempts, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Trust Tags</strong> enable businesses to define, categorize, tag and differentiate between good and bad users, devices, locations or personas.</li>
<li><strong>SmartID</strong> identifies returning users that wipe cookies, use private browsing, and change other parameters to bypass traditional device fingerprinting tools. This improves returning user detection and reduces false positives.</li>
<li><strong>TrueIP</strong> accurately detects the use of location and identity cloaking services, such as hidden proxies and VPNs, allowing your business to see the true IP address, geolocation and other attributes of each transaction.</li>
</ul>


<p>Whoa nelly those are some impressive features! Ok let&rsquo;s break this down. Obviously the port scan is only a part of the solution. But combine that with other data collected on the user, then cross reference that with other data and these companies can develop a rich understanding of the user. The more the company knows about the user the better they can serve the user. Or track the user. Or deliver custom ads for the user. In some ways the user benefits but in many ways the user is losing a lot of privacy.</p>

<p>But fraud reduction seems to be the big reason why websites are doing this. If you noticed, all the ports scanned are related to remote access to a computer. There are a lot of scams where an attacker will take control of the victims computer, then try to buy something on Amazon or send money from the victim&rsquo;s bank to the attacker&rsquo;s bank. Websites have seen a lot of chargebacks, saying they didn&rsquo;t buy something that was purchased on their account. When the website tracks this purchase it shows it was from the same browser the user usually uses, the same IP everything. But the computer was remotely controlled. So by checking if any ports are open which would indicate the computer is being remotely controlled, this can help websites combat unauthorized purchases.</p>

<p>Besides helping victims stay safe from this kind of attack, websites have also seen fraudsters purchase server space in the cloud then use that server to try different usernames and passwords with. Because the fraudster can just cancel their cloud server and get a new one and the website can&rsquo;t track them. So this is another reason why websites want to know if their visitors are being remotely controlled.</p>

<h2>Is this illegal?</h2>

<p>Ah the burning debate. Recently NordVPN Tweeted this:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.tunnelsup.com/images/portscan3.jpg" width="300px"></p>

<p>And a lot of the InfoSec community piled on NordVPN for saying such ridiculous things. I think we didn&rsquo;t understand that this kind of javascript browser local port scanning is even a thing. So it made no sense to us that a browser extension can block this. But also with companies like Shodan.io who portscan the entire internet legally, everyone was saying port scanning is not illegal. I mean if you open port 80 on your server and someone checks to see if it&rsquo;s open, that&rsquo;s perfectly legal. This Tweet resulted in a lot of people calling NordVPN bad names. So did NordVPN say anything wrong here?</p>

<p>To begin with this kind of port scanning is totally different than what Shodan is doing. Shodan is going to every IP on the <strong>public internet</strong> and checking what ports are open. But what eBay is doing is port scanning my PC in my private network in my home. Which is behind a firewall, and it&rsquo;s a restricted network! It&rsquo;s the difference between someone driving by my home, and looking to see if I left my front door open vs someone coming INTO my home, and checking if my bedroom door is open. I can&rsquo;t control what goes on outside my house and I get it&rsquo;s public space. But I do not authorize anyone to port scan computers inside my house! So at least to me I do not consent to this, and this is not ok with me.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at this Tweet from <strong>2018</strong>.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Halifax Bank are illegally carrying out a local port scan, checking for open VNC/RDP ports. Without consent, this breaches CMA. They disagree, 3 solicitors agree.<br><br>Is anyone brave enough to take this on?<br><br>cc <a href="https://twitter.com/BBCTech?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BBCTech</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/ruskin147?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ruskin147</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/jleyden?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@jleyden</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Chrisitv?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Chrisitv</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinpashby?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@kevinpashby</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/dangoodin001?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dangoodin001</a> <a href="https://t.co/BSAwXWzTKb">pic.twitter.com/BSAwXWzTKb</a></p>&mdash; Paul Moore 🇬🇧 (@Paul_Reviews) <a href="https://twitter.com/Paul_Reviews/status/1025445964910350336?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 3, 2018</a></blockquote>


<p> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>Back in 2018 Paul saw that halifax.co.uk was port scanning his PC when he visited it. Paul believes this is a direct violation of the <a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/1990/18/contents">Computer Misuse Act in the UK</a>. And right in section 1 part 1 a it says:</p>

<blockquote><p>A person is guilty of an offense if—he causes a computer to perform any function with intent to secure access to any program or data held in any computer</p></blockquote>

<p>That is quite a broad statement! It&rsquo;s saying anyone who accesses any secure data on a computer is guilty of the CMA. This is a double edge sword. On one hand yes this does mean that accessing information about what ports I have on my personal computer is illegal, but on the other hand, you can use this to convict anyone. This is just way too broad to be used as a basis for anything!</p>

<p>So I think a judge will then have to look for intent. Does ThreatMetrix have <em>intent</em> on doing something malicious or harmful with the secure data they acquired through this scan? At the surface, no. They are doing this to improve customer experience and combat fraud. But what if they are negligent with their own security and get breached and now a ton of personal data about me is leaked. I did not opt in to give this data to ThreatMetrix. So if they are negligent with my data then yes absolutely they can be fined and face punishments by a court.</p>

<p>Halifax bank, which is owned by Lloyds Banking Group, which is a listed as client of ThreatMetrix, was never brought to court for this and continues to use this software.</p>

<p>This is one of those situations that this has gone right up to the edge of the line on whether it&rsquo;s legal or not. It&rsquo;s a gray area. And in this case it seems to be used for good (although I don&rsquo;t approve), but what happens when websites adopt this technology with malicious intent? Then this port scanning behavior will become criminal activity.</p>

<p>A journalist at Forbes <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2020/05/25/did-you-know-ebay-is-probing-your-computer-heres-how-to-stop-it-windows-privacy-chrome-firefox-web-browser/#16ca00e93a92">reached out to eBay</a> for a comment and they said:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Our customers’ privacy and data remain a top priority. We are committed to creating an experience on our sites and services that is safe, secure, and trustworthy.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>And that makes sense. They are doing this to improve security of eBay&rsquo;s assets, but it&rsquo;s at the expense of giving personal information of users to ThreatMetrix. So is the gain better than the loss?</p>

<p>This also doesn&rsquo;t seem to be adhering to GDPR data privacy regulations. So this probably in direct violation of that at the minimum.</p>

<p>Lastly you should take a look at this. <a href="https://pastebin.com/RjDeDJZq">Here is a sample of data</a> that ThreatMetrix collects on each visitor to the site through their js tracking tools.</p>

<p>This reminds me of <a href="https://panopticlick.eff.org/">Panopticlick</a>. If you run the test and click show additional data, you&rsquo;ll see how much info a website can collect on you. I ran it, and my browser data was completely unique compared to the hundreds of thousands of others who ran it. Meaning all this data my browser gave the websites means they can track me even if refuse to allow cookies and other tracking methods.</p>

<p>If I had more time I would try playing with the javascript to see if I could get it to port scan other devices in my local network. Because I think that would be going over the line on legalities. I&rsquo;m not a lawyer so I don&rsquo;t know. But what I&rsquo;ve seen from court history is that it&rsquo;s not the law that matters, it&rsquo;s whoever has the better lawyer that wins.</p>

<p>So maybe we owe NordVPN an apology for piling on them like that. They have removed their Tweet due to the enormous backlash they got. They weren&rsquo;t saying that a VPN can fix it, instead they were <a href="https://nordvpn.com/blog/use-these-browser-extensions-for-your-privacy/">linking to a blog post showing what browser extensions can help keep you more secure</a>, which is a fine blog post. Those extensions do block this port scanning. I don&rsquo;t think they deserved the backlash they got from that Tweet. This is a real problem and quite possibly illegal if not now, then it will be soon when someone abuses this.</p>

<h2>Wait, technically, how is this possible?</h2>

<p>Ya good question. Well for this I defer to Dan Nemec who breaks down the javascript involved.</p>

<p><a href="https://blog.nem.ec/2020/05/24/ebay-port-scanning/">https://blog.nem.ec/2020/05/24/ebay-port-scanning/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highlights from DEFCON 25]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/highlights-from-defcon-25/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-09T12:55:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/highlights-from-defcon-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DEFCON 25 is now over. The largest hacking conference in the world continues to grow larger each year. Previous years there were 18-22,000 attendees. This year over 23,000 people made it to Ceasars Palace for the talks, workshops, parties, and social activities.</p>

<p>Here are some notable highlights from the event.</p>

<h2>On Lockdown</h2>

<p>When DEFCON rolls into town, some shops close their shutters to avoid potential threats. In previous years we&rsquo;ve seen the neon signs become blue screened, and many other pranks and shenanigans. This year we saw this.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.tunnelsup.com/images/defcon25-2.png">
<img src="https://www.tunnelsup.com/images/defcon25-1.png"></p>

<p>It doesn&rsquo;t seem like UPS gets it.</p>

<h2>Voting machines not as secure as you think.</h2>

<p>The big news this event is the voting machines. A total of 30 different voting machines were brought to the conference to test their security, and hilarity ensued.</p>

<p>The machines were put on the network and people were encouraged to attack them through the network. In the first 90 minutes, the first voting machine was popped. And soon additional voting machines were also found to have weak security.</p>

<p>It seems these machines weren&rsquo;t updated with patches and had additional weak security controls. When one attendee got into a machine they found the machine was still holding 650,000 voter names and votes. This was a machine that was purchased on ebay. So not only are the machine weak the data on them isn&rsquo;t being looked after properly. Another machine was found to be able to remotely change the votes on the system by a hacker.</p>

<p>Many attendees were saying the slot machines in the casino&rsquo;s are more secure than the voting machines we use to run our democratic way of life. And this is true. The slot machines undergo strict audits, not only by the game makers, but also by the gaming board. Slot machines have a long history of being secure and bug free. We all hope this is an eye opener for voting machine companies and government to take the security of these more seriously.</p>

<p><a href="https://gizmodo.com/personal-info-of-650-000-voters-discovered-on-poll-mach-1797438462">Further reading >></a></p>

<h2>Is a Car Wash Secure?</h2>

<p>Security researchers Billy Rios of WhiteScope Security and Jonathan Butts of QED Secure Solutions gave a talk that demonstrates how they can remotely take over a car wash. In this demonstration they were able to close the bay doors of the car wash and change the behavior of the spray jets. They did this through a network based attack where they could have been on the other side of the globe.</p>

<p>One reason someone might want to do this is to physically harm or trap a person in a car wash. By letting the bay doors down at the right time it can smash the car and driver which can severely impact the car and driver.</p>

<p>To be safe, maybe avoid car washes that have automatic bay doors that can trap you inside.</p>

<p><a href="https://nypost.com/2017/08/01/hackers-are-now-targeting-car-washes/amp/">Further reading >></a></p>

<h2>Work Badges Easily Cloned</h2>

<p>At DEFCON 18 I first saw someone close a security badge. The ones you might get at work, or give you access to a gated community or something. The equipment then was clunky and slow. You needed to be almost touching the badge and it would take a while.</p>

<p>The technology has improved tremendously for cloning these badges. A talk was given by Dennis Maldonado that demonstrated he can read the data of a badge from 2 feet away and then send that another 30 feet away to be processed.</p>

<p>He was able to take it a step further and make the whole thing trigger from his Pebble watch and an Android app.</p>

<p>To avoid being attacked like this and having your badge cloned without you knowing it, keep it in a safe place when not using it and consider using and RF blocker wallet to store it in.</p>

<p><a href="https://mashable.com/2017/07/27/rfid-cloning-made-easy-defcon/#u5CjK3MdRPq4">Further reading >></a></p>

<h2>Safe Cracking Robot</h2>

<p>Sparkfun founder Nathan Seidle built a combination lock cracking robot.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.tunnelsup.com/images/defcon25-3.png"></p>

<p>To demonstrate it, he bought a safe from Home Depot, attached his robot to it, and within 30 minutes the robot cracked the safe. The robot would rotate the knob back and forth feeling for just the right tension to open the safe. It needed to try numerous combinations to finally get it, but it was able to do it rapidly enough to be able to demonstrate it live on stage.</p>

<p>This certainly makes the future of safes and locks an interesting concept. This is something you might see in a sci fi movie, and is now becoming a reality.</p>

<p><a href="https://mashable.com/2017/07/28/safe-cracking-robot-defcon/#Dd6Zbft5RgqP">Further reading>></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to edit iptables so it persists through reboot CentOS]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/how-to-edit-iptables-so-it-persists-through-reboot-centos/"/>
    <updated>2017-06-11T23:13:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/how-to-edit-iptables-so-it-persists-through-reboot-centos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Usually iptables are controlled by the <strong>root</strong> user or someone with <strong>sudoer</strong> privs.</p>

<p>You can check what iptables rules there are using:</p>

<p><code>iptables -L -n</code></p>

<p>That lists all the rules, and doesn&rsquo;t resolve port names or IP addresses.</p>

<p>To edit the rules, edit the following file:</p>

<p><code>/etc/sysconfig/iptables</code></p>

<p>Then you can reload those rules by doing the following:</p>

<p><code>/etc/init.d/iptables restart</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux TTY and Terminal Commands]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/linux-tty-and-terminal-commands/"/>
    <updated>2017-05-03T11:19:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/linux-tty-and-terminal-commands</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few notes for using the Linux TTY terminal.</p>

<h2>Switch Terminals</h2>

<p>You can switch TTY terminals by doing:</p>

<p><code>CNTRL</code>+<code>ALT</code>+<code>F#</code></p>

<p>F2 will take you to TTY2, F3 TTY3 etc.</p>

<p>If you are using a Linux GUI, you can still use this combo to switch to the console. To get back to the GUI do <code>CNTRL</code>+<code>ALT</code>+<code>F7</code>.</p>

<h2>Scrolling</h2>

<p>If you need to scroll up or town while at the console, do:</p>

<p><code>SHIFT</code>+<code>PG UP/DOWN</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using The Built-In macOS FTP, TFTP, SFTP, and HTTP Servers]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.tunnelsup.com/using-the-built-in-macos-ftp-tftp-sftp-and-http-servers/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-21T22:02:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.tunnelsup.com/using-the-built-in-macos-ftp-tftp-sftp-and-http-servers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The macOS and OSX operating systems come with built in FTP, TFTP, SFTP, and HTTP servers. Here is how to enable them and use them.</p>

<h2>FTP Server</h2>

<p>To start an FTP server use this terminal command:</p>

<p><code>
sudo -s launchctl load -w /System/Library/LaunchDaemons/ftp.plist
</code></p>

<p>Users will need to authenticate to the macOS system using standard logins that are already on the macOS. When someone logs in, they will arrive in <code>/Users/&lt;username&gt;/</code>.</p>

<p>To stop the FTP server, run the following:</p>

<p><code>
sudo launchctl unload -F /System/Library/LaunchDaemons/ftp.plist
</code></p>

<h2>TFTP Server</h2>

<p><code>
sudo launchctl load -F /System/Library/LaunchDaemons/tftp.plist
sudo launchctl start com.apple.tftpd
</code></p>

<p>The directory that serves files is <code>/private/tftpboot</code>.</p>

<p>To stop the TFTP server, either reboot or use this command:</p>

<p><code>
sudo launchctl unload -F /System/Library/LaunchDaemons/tftp.plist
</code></p>

<h2>SFTP Server</h2>

<p>This one is different. Go to system preferences then <code>Sharing</code>. Check the box to enabe <code>Remote Login</code>. Once this is done, other people will be able to ssh and sftp to your macOS system.</p>

<h2>HTTP Server</h2>

<p>Apache comes bundled with macOS. To start it, run this command.</p>

<p><code>
sudo apachectl start
</code></p>

<p>By default the files will be served from <code>/Library/WebServer/Documents</code>.</p>

<p>To disable the server, either reboot or do this command:</p>

<p><code>
sudo apachectl stop
</code></p>

<h2>Checking Status</h2>

<p>To check to see what&rsquo;s running, run the command:</p>

<p><code>
netstat -an | grep LISTEN
</code></p>

<p>This will show you which ports are open on your macOS. For example if you have Apache running, you will see the following:</p>

<p><code>
tcp46      0      0  *.80                   *.*                    LISTEN
</code></p>

<ul>
<li>HTTP = TCP 80</li>
<li>FTP = TCP 21</li>
<li>SSH = TCP 22</li>
<li>SFTP = TCP 22</li>
<li>TFTP = UDP 69</li>
</ul>


<p>Note that TFTP is on UDP and won&rsquo;t say listen. Just run <code>netstat -an | grep 69</code> to find if it&rsquo;s running.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
